<?xml version="1.0"?>
<week>
    <week1>
        <description>Most OBs count pregnancy starting from the first day of your last period. That's because ovulation and conception are really tough to pinpoint, but the physical signs of menstruation are much easier to spot. So in doctor speak, 1 week pregnant means you’re on your period and not yet pregnant. You won’t actually conceive your baby until week two or three, depending on the length of your cycle.

            If you’ve just found out you’re expecting, you might think this is your first week of pregnancy, but you’re probably around 4 weeks pregnant. Yes, already! (Your OB will give you a more accurate estimate when you go in for your first prenatal appointment.) Skip ahead and check out week 4.</description>
        <symptoms>At 1 week pregnant—remember at this early stage, the symptoms you're experiencing are those typical to your period because you're not actually pregnant. These symptoms may last from three to seven days, and can include:
            Vaginal bleeding. You body is shedding the uterine lining, which holds last month’s unfertilized egg.
            Lower back pain and cramps. To release that lining, your uterus contracts, causing your back and abdomen to ache.
            Bloating. Fluctuating hormones can give you a bloated belly right before and during your period.
            Mood swings. Those raging hormones can also cause irritability and wreak havoc on your emotions.
            Headache. Many women complain of menstrual migraines, which are also hormone related. (Surprise, surprise.) Ice packs, OTC pain relievers, and relaxation exercises may help ease the pain.</symptoms>
        <belly>Inside your 1 week pregnant belly, your body isn’t only releasing last month’s egg. It begins to form a new uterine lining, which will hold next month’s egg. You know, the one that will hopefully get fertilized and grow and develop into a fetus?!
            Cool fact: Human eggs are the largest cells in the body. An egg is the size of peach fuzz. Your body will release one (or in rare cases, two) eggs somewhere between day 10 and day 19 of your menstrual cycle—or about 14 days before your next period is expected. It can be fertilized for about 12 to 24 hours after that. Oh, and having sex before then is helpful too, since sperm can live in your body for up to six days.
            The first signs of pregnancy won’t occur right away—in fact, many women miss their period at week 4 before they even feel “different.” But some common early signs of pregnancy in the first weeks after fertilization include breast soreness or tenderness, nausea, fatigue, and frequent urge to pee.
            At one week pregnant (a.k.a. hoping to be pregnant soon!), you’re probably thinking about how you can prep your body to carry a baby. It’s a good idea to start pregnancy at a healthy weight and free of bad habits such as smoking and drinking. Reduce your caffeine intake to the equivalent of a cup of coffee or two (we’re talking 8 ounce cups—not the venti!) per day.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Stop unhealthy habits such as smoking, drinking, and excessive caffeine,2.Take a prenatal vitamin with 400 mcg folic acid daily,3.Track your cycle to pinpoint your most fertile days,</checklist>
    </week1>

    <week2>
        <description>Most OBs count pregnancy starting from the first day of your last menstrual period (LMP). Yep, that’s a week or two before you even get pregnant. We know it sounds totally weird, but it’s more accurate for doctors to estimate a due date this way.
            So if you think you conceived about two weeks ago, you’re probably at least four weeks pregnant—maybe even five. We give you permission to skip ahead to week four.
            If you really are in the second week of your cycle and are trying to conceive, we’ve got some advice right here for you.</description>
        <symptoms>Getting pregnant relies on timing sex for when you’re most fertile—this is probably in the two days before you ovulate and the day you actually ovulate. If you’ve got a regular 28-day cycle, chances are you ovulate on day 15. But who the heck has a regular 28-day cycle every month?
            At 2 weeks pregnant, symptoms of ovulation can clue you in on the best time to have sex and hopefully conceive a baby. You’re probably ovulating if you notice these signs at week 2 of pregnancy:
            “Egg white” cervical mucus. Sounds a little gross, but it’s true. Your cervical mucus becomes thin, clear, and stringy, like egg whites, as you near ovulation. This consistency helps sperm travel toward the egg.
            Better sense of smell. Believe it! Hormonal changes boost your ability to pick up different scents, which is probably nature’s way of helping you sniff out male pheromones in an effort to procreate.
            Breast soreness or tenderness. Hormone changes associated with ovulation can make your boobs feel slightly sore.
            Pelvic ache. As your ovary releases an egg, you might feel a little twinge in one side of your abdomen. This is the phenomenon known as Mittelschmerz—named for the doctor who first documented it.
            Light spotting. You might notice a small tinge of red or brown on your underwear around the time of ovulation. This happens when the follicle around the egg ruptures. If it’s actual bleeding though, it could be something else, such as an ectopic pregnancy, so let your doctor know if you experience something heavier than just spotting in between periods.
            Increased sex drive. You might “just know” that you’re ovulating and naturally get revved up for some baby-making sex.
            Cervical changes. If you check your cervix routinely—something women who chart often do—you may notice it becomes higher, softer, and more open when you’re ovulating.
            Some women buy an ovulation test to help them figure out when they might be most fertile. A low-tech strategy is to have sex every other day from about day 12 to day 16 of your menstrual cycle—meaning toward the end of the second week to the beginning of the third.</symptoms>
        <belly>If you do conceive at 2 weeks pregnant, symptoms won’t appear right away. In fact, you won’t be able to find out for sure you’re if pregnant until there’s enough pregnancy hormones in your system for a home pregnancy test to detect. That should happen at about week 4, which is the same time you’ll probably miss your period. Around this time, those hormone levels are finally high enough that they give you some noticeable pregnancy symptoms. Some women swear they do start noticing early pregnancy signs before week 4 though; these are the ones that could clue you in:
            Spotting. About 5 to 10 days after conception, you may notice a little spotting. This is caused by the embryo implanting itself into your uterine wall.
            Frequent urination. Pregnancy hormones can cause you to take more trips to the bathroom in the first weeks of pregnancy.
            Sore boobs and/or darker areolas. Pretty much as soon as those hormones appear, a woman’s body starts prepping her boobs for breastfeeding.
            Fatigue. Total exhaustion is some women’s first clue they’re expecting. That’s because your body will use a ton of energy to grow baby.
            Morning sickness. Probably the most notorious pregnancy symptom, nausea usually begins to rear its ugly head around week 4 to week 9.
            Bloating. Yes, again. As your body starts to realize you’re pregnant, it will probably slow down the digestion process in an effort to deliver more nutrients to baby. This can result in a bit of gas and bloating—hey, maybe it will even look a bit like a 2 weeks pregnant belly! (Not that that exists!)</belly>
        <checklist>1.Consider using an ovulation test,2.Look for signs of ovulation,3.Have sex every other day as you near your fertile period,4.Keep taking a prenatal vitamin with folic acid daily,</checklist>
    </week2>

    <week3>
        <description>Sperm met egg last week, and voila—you've made a baby! It’s so ridiculously early that when you’re 3 weeks pregnant, you may have no idea that you’re actually pregnant. Conception just happened a few days ago, and there probably hasn't been time for you to miss a period yet at week 3 of pregnancy.</description>
        <symptoms>When you’re 3 weeks pregnant, symptoms may not have appeared yet either. That’s because most early pregnancy symptoms are caused by pregnancy hormones, and you probably don’t have a very high level of those in your body yet. (Oh, but you’ll get there!) Some signs of pregnancy at 3 weeks—and the few weeks following—are:
            Implantation bleeding. If your little soon-to-be-embryo has already made it to his or her new home, you may see a bit of spotting as the fertilized egg burrows into the wall of your uterus.
            Nausea. As the pregnancy hormone hCG begins to make its way through your newly pregnant body, you may notice some feelings of queasiness—or nausea so bad it makes you puke. Morning sickness should really be called all-day sickness since it really doesn’t discriminate by time of day. If you’re feeling this symptom of pregnancy at three weeks, you may be further along than you thought. (Or—not to freak you out or anything, but—you may even be three weeks pregnant with twins! That’s because twin moms-to-be often have higher levels of pregnancy hormones—and therefore worse nausea.)
            Breast changes. Your boobs can start to get sore and your nipples may darken as your body starts prepping to make milk.
            Missed period. If your cycle is typically shorter than 28 days, you may realize toward the end of this week that you could be pregnant. The only way to know for sure is to take a pregnancy test.
            Positive home pregnancy test. Check the box of your home pregnancy test to see how accurate its results are before your missed period. Most are over 99% accurate once you’ve missed it, and some brands promise to detect pregnancy hormones in your urine sooner than that. (For example, when you’re 3 weeks 5 days pregnant or even 3 weeks 4 days pregnant.) Here’s the thing: The amount of pregnancy hormone hCG in your body might not be enough for the test to detect right away—but it doubles every 48 hours. If you get a negative result, follow up a few days and then a week later with another pregnancy test and then another, to be sure it wasn’t just too early to tell.
            Positive blood pregnancy test. In some cases—like if you’re at risk for miscarriage or ectopic pregnancy—your doctor may ask you to come into the office for a blood draw. Blood tests can detect smaller amounts of hCG than urine tests can, so you may find out that you’re pregnant sooner with a blood test than you would with an at-home test.</symptoms>
        <belly>You may be excited to start noticing something different about your appearance, but at 3 weeks pregnant, a belly isn’t really a thing. Though you may feel a bit bloated, most pregnant women don’t start to show until around week 12, so you’ve got quite a way to go before you actually look pregnant.
            Before you start eating for two, know that doctors only recommend most women gain three to five pounds total in the first trimester—that’s the first 13 weeks. So you definitely don’t have license to start indulging at three weeks pregnant. In fact, you shouldn’t really do anything different except try to eat a healthy, well-rounded diet and to take a daily prenatal vitamin with at least 400 micrograms of folic acid in it. Doctors don’t recommend increasing your daily calorie intake until the second trimester either. Once you hit week 14, you’ll want to add about 300 (healthy) calories per day.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Calculate your due date,2.Take an early result pregnancy test,3.Keep taking a prenatal vitamin with folic acid daily,4.Read up on the first trimester,</checklist>
    </week3>

    <week4>
        <description>Congratulations! If you know you're 4 weeks pregnant, you found out the news earlier than a lot of women do (because you took a test as soon as you missed your period, or even a few days before, instead of waiting a bit)—and you might be totally excited, or you might be getting used to the idea of having a baby. Either way, you may not be feeling any different (for now, at least), since early pregnancy symptoms don’t always kick in right away. Definitely celebrate this amazing news with your partner, but you may not want to tell the whole world… just yet. Your first call at week 4 of pregnancy should be to your doctor to schedule your first prenatal visit, where he or she will confirm your pregnancy with a urine or blood test.
            How Big Is Baby at 4 Weeks Pregnant?
            At 4 weeks pregnant, baby is smaller than a poppy seed—practically microscopic. Baby is now known as a blastocyst, a teeny ball of cells, and is busy settling into his or her new home (your uterus), prepping for all the crucial development that will happen over the next six weeks.</description>
        <symptoms>The same pregnancy hormones that gave you that positive pregnancy test can also cause some of the more typical 4-week pregnancy symptoms. These hormone levels increase pretty quickly, so while it’s normal to be 4 weeks pregnant with no symptoms, brace yourself: nausea and vomiting may be in your near future. Here’s a bit of what to expect at 4 weeks pregnant:
            Bloating. You may be a little puffed up thanks to the pregnancy hormone progesterone. Break out the comfy pants!
            Mild cramping. At 4 weeks pregnant cramping might worry you, but it actually may be a sign that baby has properly implanted in the wall of your uterus. However, any severe cramping or pain at 4 weeks pregnant is something you should definitely tell your doctor about right away. He or she will want to examine you to rule out any problems.
            Spotting. Light bleeding can also occur during week 4 as a result of implantation. Don't worry—this is totally normal too. But the same advice goes: If it’s a lot of blood, like a period or heavier, lasts for more than a couple days, or if you’re concerned in any way, see the doc.
            Mood swings. It’s not your imagination. Your mood is going haywire mostly because of your fluctuating hormones. (But maybe also because of stress and because your mind is racing.) Pregnancy mood swings are most drastic during the first 12 weeks. After that, the hormones will level out a bit, making you less likely to cry at every life insurance commercial you see.
            Morning sickness. Experts say that about 50 to 90 percent of pregnant women get some form of morning sickness (a.k.a. nausea and sometimes vomiting too). So even if you haven’t had an upset stomach yet, you probably will at some point. Morning sickness is usually at its worst around nine weeks and then slowly gets better, typically disappearing completely in the second trimester.
            Fatigue. One of the most common four weeks pregnant symptoms is total exhaustion, as your body is working hard to grow that teeny ball of cells into an embryo.
            Sore breasts. Yowch! Your boobs are swollen and tender because of those surging hormones telling your body, “There’s a baby coming. Better start prepping those milk ducts!”</symptoms>
        <belly>A 4 weeks pregnant belly might be a little bloated, but you almost certainly don’t look pregnant yet. Still, you need to start acting like a mom-to-be. And that means giving TLC to yourself and your tiny baby-to-be.
            Baby is already undergoing important development at week 4 of pregnancy, so start taking a prenatal vitamin if you’re not already. Look for one with at least 400 micrograms of folic acid and remember to take it daily. We know you’ve got a lot on your mind, but since folic acid is proven to help prevent birth defects, this is super important!
            As your skinny jeans get more difficult to button, don’t shy away from looser clothing styles. Think stretchy pants, leggings, drapey shirts, and waterfall cardigans. There are a ton of loose-fitting clothing options that will help you look stylish and stay comfy.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Find an OB and make your first prenatal appointment,2.Quit drinking and smoking,3.Start taking a prenatal vitamin,4.Tell your partner you're pregnant,</checklist>
    </week4>

    <week5>
        <description>You’ve just been initiated to the pregnancy club! Week 5 is a common time for moms-to-be to find out they’re pregnant. That’s because by now you’ve probably realized you’ve missed your period and then thought, Whoa… maybe I should take a test! Plus, at 5 weeks pregnant, heightened hormone levels may be giving you symptoms that are tough to ignore, like sore breasts, nausea, and fatigue. (Those same hormones are the ones your pregnancy test detected to give you a positive result.) Okay, so the “club” might not be so fun right now, but you’ll eventually be so glad you were a member. Just give it, oh, about eight more months.
            How Big Is Baby at 5 Weeks Pregnant?
            At 5 weeks pregnant, baby is the size of an apple seed. Yep, your embryo is now measurable—though at week five of pregnancy, it's a wee 0.13 inches from crown to rump (a.k.a. head to bum)—and baby's gearing up for much more growth. In fact, in the next week, he or she will almost double in size. Grow, baby, grow!
            5 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            5 weeks pregnant is about one month pregnant. Yep, you just discovered you’re pregnant and you’ve already got one month in the books. That’s because most doctors start counting pregnancy from the first day of your last period. Only eight months to go!</description>
        <symptoms>The pregnancy symptoms you feel at five weeks are just the beginning of the slew of changes your body is about to go through. No need to dread the entire pregnancy based on what’s happening right now: many moms-to-be say the first trimester is the toughest, so think of it as getting the rough stuff out of the way early. In the meantime, take care of yourself and get plenty of rest, eat right, and figure out ways to help yourself feel better. If you’re wondering what to expect at 5 weeks pregnant, here’s what’s most common:
            Sore breasts. Morning sickness gets all the attention, but aching boobs may actually be the most common symptom at 5 weeks pregnant.
            Morning sickness. This bad boy is so inaccurately named. Nausea in early pregnancy can happen at any time of the day, not just morning. And unfortunately, some pregnant moms feel queasy pretty much all day. In fact, if you’re 5 weeks pregnant with twins, you may be more likely to have severe morning sickness. Experiment with different strategies to find what helps you deal with the queasies best. Eating small, frequent meals is one good one. You might also try Vitamin B6, ginger capsules, special nausea-reducing lozenges or lollipops, and acupressure wristbands.
            Fatigue. At 5 weeks pregnant, it’s normal to want to nap in the middle of a board meeting, a dinner date, a… well, pretty much any time. You’re zapped from making a baby and there’s not much you can do about it except get some extra rest, do some light exercise, and eat every few hours so your blood sugar doesn’t drop so much that you lose even more of your (already scarce) energy.
            Frequent urination. You might notice yourself having the urge to pee more often early in pregnancy. This symptom at 5 weeks pregnant is because your kidneys are actually expanding. (Whoa!)
            Cramps. Around 4 or 5 weeks, cramping could be a sign the embryo has implanted nicely into the lining of your uterus. Or it could be a sign your uterus is expanding and stretching your ligaments. If you’re feeling cramping at 5 weeks pregnant that’s severe or painful, call your doctor and get checked out to make sure it’s not a sign of a problem.
            Spotting. When you’re 5 weeks pregnant spotting can seem scary, but a little blood on your underwear could also be a sign of implantation. You might also spot a bit after sex, since your cervix is more sensitive now that you’re pregnant. This is totally normal, but if you’re having something that’s less like spotting and more like bleeding at 5 weeks pregnant—or really, if you’re concerned at all—call the doctor.
            Some moms-to-be who are 5 weeks pregnant feel no symptoms at all. Or it might feel like, at 5 weeks pregnant, symptoms come and go. And all of that is totally okay! Just because you’re not feeling sick or sore doesn’t mean there’s something wrong with the pregnancy. It just means you’re lucky!</symptoms>
        <belly>At 5 weeks pregnant, your belly may look unchanged—or you may be a bit bloated or feel like you’ve already gained a pound. Heck, you might feel so sick that you can’t eat and worry you could have lost a pound. All those scenarios are considered perfectly normal and totally okay! All pregnant women are different and how their bodies change throughout pregnancy varies widely.
            You’re probably starting to wonder a bit about overall pregnancy weight gain. The short answer is: You don’t need to worry too much about it yet. Doctors only recommend gaining a few pounds (1 to 5 to be exact) during the first trimester (which ends after week 13), and that will probably happen without you thinking too much about it.
            The long answer is that you will need to gain weight.
            Your doctor will discuss personalized weight gain recommendations with you—know that they vary based on body type. Here’s what the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists (ACOG) recommends:
            If you’re underweight (BMI under 18.5):
            Your recommended total pregnancy weight gain is 28 to 40 pounds.
            In the second and third trimesters, aim to gain about a pound (1 to 1.3 pounds to be exact) per week.
            If you’re of average weight (BMI of 18.5 to 24.9):
            Your recommended total pregnancy weight gain is 25 to 35 pounds.
            In the second and third trimesters, aim to gain about a pound or a little less (0.8 to 1 pound to be exact) per week.
            If you’re overweight (BMI of 25 to 29.9):
            Your recommended total pregnancy weight gain is 15 to 25 pounds.
            In the second and third trimesters, aim to gain a little over a half pound (0.5 to 0.7 pound to be exact) per week.
            If you’re obese (BMI of 30 and above):
            Your recommended total pregnancy weight gain is 11 to 20 pounds.
            In the second and third trimesters, aim to gain about a half pound (0.4 to 0.6 pound to be exact) per week.
            If you’re 5 weeks pregnant with twins:
            Your recommended total pregnancy weight gain is 37 to 54 pounds.
            In the first half of pregnancy, aim to gain about a pound per week. In the second half, gain a little over a pound per week.
            Wondering if you could be 5 weeks pregnant with twins? If you were, you probably wouldn’t know it yet, though as we mentioned above, some twin moms swear they had worse morning sickness. They also may gain weight more rapidly and “start to show” earlier than women having one baby would.
            5 weeks pregnant is a good time ask your partner for a massage. You might not have a big bump, but at five weeks pregnant, your body is working fast and furiously to grow baby, so you deserve a little TLC, right?</belly>
        <checklist>1.Establish a healthy diet,2.Start a pregnancy journal,3.Come up with a plan to save for baby,</checklist>
    </week5>

    <week6>
        <description>Has the news sunk in yet? At week six, pregnancy is still new to you, so it’s normal to feel a little emotional. Add to that some pretty uncomfortable early pregnancy symptoms (which include hormone fluctuations that can feel like PMS—on steroids!), and it’s understandable to feel downright miserable. Did we mention nervous and uncertain? That’s probably part of why you have nine whole months to adjust to pregnancy. Of course, it’s also because baby needs all that time to get all his or her working parts in order.
            How Big Is Baby at 6 Weeks?
            At 6 weeks pregnant, baby is the size of a sweet pea. The average embryo at week six is about .25 inches and will double in size again next week. Wow!
            6 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            At 6 weeks, you’re one month and about one week pregnant—even though it’s probably been only a week or two (or even less) since you found out you were expecting. That’s because pregnancy is measured starting with the first day of your last menstrual period. You probably conceived in week 2 or 3 (depending on the length of your menstrual cycle) and didn’t discover your pregnancy until you missed your period around week 5.</description>
        <symptoms>Because it’s still early in your pregnancy, you may not yet be experiencing symptoms—at this point, some women are terribly nauseous, while others feel almost nothing. At 6 weeks pregnant, either is normal, but the most common 6 weeks pregnant symptoms include:
            Fatigue. You’re so drained because your body's still getting used to your changing hormones. Get extra rest if you’re feeling wiped out.
            Nausea. Hate to break it, but morning sickness doesn't just happen in the morning. It can be an all-day affair. And moms-to-be who are six weeks pregnant with twins might have even more severe nausea. It’s a good idea to find foods that help settle your stomach and to keep them on hand for regular snacking, since having an empty stomach can trigger bouts of nausea.
            Sore breasts. Your boobs are likely sore thanks to increased blood flow. Can you believe your body is already starting to prep to breastfeed your baby? Yep, even at just six weeks!
            Frequent urination. If you find yourself having to pee more than usual, it’s because the pregnancy hormone hCG is directing extra blood flow to the pelvic area. Heading to the bathroom more often is normal, but if you have painful urination or have the urge to go but are unable to, tell your doctor right away. Those are signs of a UTI, which you’re at higher risk for starting at week 6 of pregnancy.
            Gas and bloating. The pregnancy hormone progesterone can cause these tummy troubles. Drink lots of water and eat fiber-rich foods to avoid constipation (yuck), which contributes to bloating (double yuck).
            Mood swings. Yup, crankiness and emotional extremes are because of the hormones. Fatigue and fluctuations in blood sugar can contribute too, so get extra rest and regularly eat healthy meals and snacks to keep your mood (at least sort of) in check.
            Cramping and spotting. At 6 weeks pregnant—and any time in early pregnancy—cramping and spotting are both normal. We know these symptoms can make you worry about problems like ectopic pregnancy at 6 weeks and other types of miscarriage. Know that if any abdominal pain is severe (stronger than period cramps) or if bleeding becomes heavy like a period, then you should call the doctor.</symptoms>
        <belly>Though it’s common to be bloated at 6 weeks pregnant, you likely don’t look pregnant at all. Inside your six weeks pregnant belly, your rapidly growing pea-sized embryo will soon take up a greater amount of real estate in your belly. So, if you’re not ready to share your news with the world, you can enjoy your little secret for a little longer. Of course, if you’re 6 weeks pregnant with twins, belly expansion will happen a little sooner than it will for other moms-to-be.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Prep for your first prenatal appointment,2.Review your life insurance policy,3.Take a relationship pulse,</checklist>
    </week6>

    <week7>
        <description>You’re keeping the best kind of secret, aren’t you? Now that you’re seven weeks pregnant, you’re going about your day knowing you’re expecting—but no one else can see it. That can give you a surreal feeling! And at week 7 of pregnancy, you’re probably wondering what things will be like once it’s obvious to everyone that you’ve got a baby growing in there. For now, enjoy your little secret.
            How Big Is a Baby at 7 Weeks?
            At 7 weeks pregnant, baby is the size of a blueberry. Your embryo measures about .51 inches, having doubled in size since last week. He or she doesn't exactly tip the scales just yet, but is developing like crazy inside your 7-week pregnant belly.
            7 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            Seven weeks pregnant means you’re one month and about two weeks pregnant.</description>
        <symptoms>Being 7 weeks pregnant can cause a whole range of symptoms. Some are no biggie and some can make it difficult to get through your day. These are a few of the most widespread:
            Nausea. Morning sickness may be going strong at week 7 of pregnancy. Hang in there, and try to find ways to cope. Some moms-to-be have success with ginger, Vitamin B-6, and acupressure wristbands easing their tummy troubles. When your hormones become more normal in the second trimester, the nausea should decrease or even disappear. Moms-to-be who are 7 weeks pregnant with twins may be more likely to have nausea and vomiting, since they likely have heightened levels of the hormones that cause morning sickness.
            Food cravings and/or aversions. You may find yourself with the urge to eat specific or even weird foods—or not wanting to go anywhere near certain foods you used to think were fine (or even delicious!). Food aversions are nature’s way of keeping you away from potentially dangerous foods, and typically go hand-in-hand with morning sickness. It's okay to give in to your cravings and indulge here and there. But try not to go too crazy, and make healthy food choices when you can. *__ Frequent urination.__ If it seems like you have the urge to pee constantly, it’s not your imagination. Even though you probably don’t look pregnant yet, your uterus has already doubled in size, and you also have increased blood flow to your pelvis.
            Acne. Breakouts are due to hormonal changes in your body. Before you use any acne fighting products, check with your doctor to make sure they’re safe during pregnancy.
            Extra saliva. Here’s a symptom you never expected! The excess saliva is probably also hormonally triggered and could be related to nausea too.
            Mood swings. Not only are your hormones out of whack, but you're probably still getting used to the idea of being pregnant, and that can make you become extra emotional.
            Cramping and/or spotting. Cramping in early pregnancy is normal. After all, there’s a lot happening inside your uterus, and even though it will be several weeks before you feel baby move, you can certainly feel plenty of cramping and pulling at this point in your pregnancy. Also, your cervix may be more sensitive now that you’re pregnant, so spotting at 7 weeks could happen after sex. These two pregnancy symptoms can be alarming, but know that in most cases, they’re not a sign of ectopic pregnancy or other types of miscarriage. If you were to have abdominal pain worse than typical menstrual cramps or bleeding during pregnancy at 7 weeks that’s heavier than a period, that would be a cause of worry, and you should call your doctor right away.
            That said, at 7 weeks pregnant, you may very well have no symptoms at all. If that’s the case, consider yourself lucky! Some moms-to-be worry that having no symptoms at 7 weeks could be a sign of a problem, but it’s absolutely not. We’ll keep reminding you that every woman experiences pregnancy slightly differently. If you have any concerns, definitely bring them up to your OB, but unless your symptoms at 7 weeks pregnant are severe or painful, it’s all likely normal.</symptoms>
        <belly>Caught yourself staring at your 7 weeks pregnant belly in the mirror—and even pushing it out to fake a baby bump, just to get a preview? Yeah, we did that too during week 7. Every mom-to-be is different, but many report starting to “show” in the middle of the second trimester when the uterus outgrows the pelvis. Moms-to-be who are 7 weeks pregnant with twins should expect to show earlier than that, but at this point, it’s nothing but bloating for everyone.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Read up on prenatal tests you can expect,2.Make some pregnancy-safe beauty swaps,3.Check which OTC medicines are safe,</checklist>
    </week7>

    <week8>
        <description>At 8 weeks pregnant, you’re wrapping up your second month of pregnancy. And while you may not be showing yet, being pregnant is probably finally starting to feel real to you; like most women, you may have your first prenatal appointment right around now. At this visit an ultrasound may be performed to determine how far along you are. You may even hear—and see—baby’s heartbeat. How cool is that?
            How Big is Baby at 8 Weeks?
            During week 8 of your pregnancy, baby is as big as a raspberry and weighs about .04 ounces and measures about .63 inches. Baby's growing about a millimeter each day.
            8 Weeks Pregnant is How Many Months?
            You are almost 2 months pregnant at 8 weeks.</description>
        <symptoms>Wondering what stinks? Probably ANYTHING and EVERYTHING. Your hormones are doing some wild things at week eight, giving you a superhuman-like sense of smell and making your stomach do flip-flops. At eight weeks pregnant, there are a host of pregnancy symptoms you could experience, (don’t get us started on those wacky pregnancy dreams!) including:
            Sore breasts. Your breasts may feel bigger, heavier, and let’s face it, sore. That’s because milk-producing lobules in your breasts are starting to expand. It’s all for a good reason: they’re prepping for breastfeeding.
            Fatigue. #Thestruggleisreal to nap at 8 weeks pregnant. Why? As your hormones fluctuate, your body produces more blood for baby, and your blood pressure and blood sugar levels are lower than they were pre-pregnancy. The best fix? Get more sleep. We know it sounds easier than it really is, but make it your number one priority to get to bed early or to sneak in a nap or four on the weekends.
            Morning sickness. Nausea could be really strong at 8 weeks, again related to those pregnancy hormones. Stay hydrated and graze on healthy snacks throughout the day. If you’re experiencing severe pregnancy nausea at 8 weeks, it might be tough to keep food down , let alone eat right, so finding options you can actually stomach is key. Some moms-to-be swear by ginger, Vitamin B-6, and acupressure wristbands to help with morning sickness—all worth a shot.
            Heightened sense of smell. Along with morning sickness comes another fun symptom: an uncanny sense of smell. Catching a whiff of an offensive odor—perhaps something that’s totally innocuous or never bothered you before—could trigger nausea, so it’s best to try to avoid the smells you’ve become sensitive to.
            Pregnancy cramps. At 8 weeks pregnant, cramping is normal. That’s because the ligaments in your abdomen are stretching as your uterus expands. If your cramping is severe or you’re worried in any way, let your doctor know.
            Constipation. If you’re having trouble going number two, you’re not alone. Constipation during pregnancy happens to about 50 percent of us. To deal, drink lots of water, eat fiber-rich fruits and veggies, and take lots of walks. If you’re still stopped up, talk to your doctor about other remedies.
            Weird dreams. If you’re having vivid and strange dreams, guess what, they’re totally normal throughout pregnancy. It’s not clear what causes these dreams—it could partly be due to new thoughts and anxieties. You’ve certainly got a lot on your mind these days!
            Spotting. It can be alarming to find that you’re spotting at 8 weeks pregnant because, yes, blood can be a sign of miscarriage. But there are some other causes of spotting in the first trimester, including sex (since your cervix may be more sensitive these days). Let your doctor know, so s/he can rule out any problems.
            If you’re 8 weeks pregnant with twins, you may feel extra tired and nauseous, since you’ve likely got a higher level of those pregnancy hormones—needed to create two babies.
            Remember: if you’re feeling nauseated, extra hungry, or extra tired, it’s all because baby’s growth is in overdrive—and because your body’s still adjusting to all those hormonal changes. Try to remind yourself it will be worth it. (Especially once you reach the second trimester, when most moms-to-be bounce back and feel more energized.)
            Also, know that no pregnancy symptoms at 8 weeks is totally normal too. So don’t worry if you’re not feeling too different yet. We promise—soon you will!</symptoms>
        <belly>Wondering if your belly is the right size at this stage? At 8 weeks pregnant, showing a bit is normal, but not showing is too! That’s because every mom and baby are different. Know that inside your 8 weeks pregnant belly, your uterus is expanding, but it just takes longer for some to show it on the outside. If, say, you’re 8 weeks pregnant with twins, it may be easier to tell you’re pregnant than it is to tell a singleton mom is expecting at this point.
            Starting in the second trimester, your OB will likely begin measuring your pregnant belly, but for now, size really doesn’t matter. Healthy weight gain in the first trimester is about one to two pounds each week, so at 8 weeks pregnant, you may have gained as much as 4 to 6 pounds. If you’ve been dealing with morning sickness though, you may have gained next to nothing—and that’s okay too. Let your doctor know if you have any concerns about your weight gain or belly size.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Schedule your 12-week prenatal visit,2.Decide whether to have a CVS test,3.Think about fun and creative ways to share your news,</checklist>
    </week8>

    <week9>
        <description>Let’s get serious for a sec. Now that you’re 9 weeks pregnant, you’re probably starting to think about how life will change when baby’s in the picture. That’s why around week nine of pregnancy, you might want to start looking for ways you and your partner can budget so you have extra cash when baby arrives. You should also consider checking out your company’s handbook to see how maternity leave is typically handled. That way, when you break the news to your boss, you’ll be prepared to discuss your expectations—and begin a potential maternity leave plan.
            How Big Is Baby at 9 Weeks?
            Baby is the size of a cherry at 9 weeks pregnant. Your 9-week fetus measures around .9 inches and weighs about .07 ounces, and his or her growth is picking up steam!
            9 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            At 9 weeks, you’re two months pregnant. This week, you and baby have made two big accomplishments: You’ve made it to month three, and baby's no longer an embryo—now baby's a fetus. That means he or she is becoming more and more baby-like, and you’re inching closer and closer to leaving the nasties of the first trimester behind you. Just one more month to go!</description>
        <symptoms>Right now, the pregnancy hormone hCG is circulating through your body at its peak level. That means at 9 weeks, some pregnancy symptoms may be at their most severe. Hang in there—you’re just weeks away from those hormones leveling out a bit, leaving you feeling a lot more like yourself. Here’s what 9 weeks pregnant symptoms you may be experiencing:
            Mood swings. Because those hormones just keep raging, and also because other symptoms—such as nausea and fatigue—are bothering you, you may find your emotions more difficult to control. Remember that it’s okay to slow your usual pace, to take breaks (to nap, to meditate, or just to veg out and binge-watch Netflix), and to avoid stressful situations for the sake of your sanity.
            Morning sickness. Up to 80 percent of pregnant women experience some form of morning sickness. It really should be called all-day sickness though! If you’re suffering from nausea, you might just be feeling a little ill, or you may be vomiting regularly. If you are 9 weeks pregnant with twins, you may find yourself with more severe morning sickness symptoms. The good and bad news is that at 9 weeks, morning sickness is likely at its worst. Do some trial and error to see what makes you feel better—many moms-to-be find that ginger, frequent meals and snacks, and vitamin B6 help ease nausea. You’re suffering now, but this too shall pass. You can get through this!
            Frequent urination. Because your uterus is expanding and because there’s major blood flow to your pelvic area, you may be heading to the bathroom more often than you did pre-pregnancy. Don’t let that stop you from drinking lots of water. It’s important that you stay hydrated. Just put more pit stops onto your mental to-do list.
            Fatigue. While your hormones are working overtime to grow and develop your 9-week fetus, you might be feeling totally zapped. Sleep more, if you can, and keep your blood sugar stable by snacking healthily throughout the day. In the second trimester, you’ll get some of your energy back.
            Nasal congestion. Surprise! Pregnancy can cause higher mucus production in the body—an unexpected symptom—so you might need to keep tissues handy.
            Headaches. Thanks again, hormones! Those surges can give you headaches—and so can dehydration, caffeine withdrawal, hunger, lack of sleep, and stress. Deal by treating your other symptoms, eating at least every few hours, getting plenty of sleep, and drinking lots of water. A warm or cold compress can ease a headache and so can rest. Before you take any medication, clear it with your doctor. Many say acetaminophen (Tylenol) is okay but aspirin and ibuprofen (Advil) aren’t. It will depend on your health history and any other medications you may be taking.</symptoms>
        <belly>Many moms-to-be find themselves struggling to button their jeans at 9 weeks pregnant. Your uterus is expanding to accommodate your growing fetus. In fact, it has doubled in size! When you touch your 9 weeks pregnant belly, you’ll probably find that your lower abdomen feels a bit firmer—that’s the uterus. You may even be showing a bit at 9 weeks! Your uterus will begin to grow out of your pelvis in coming weeks.
            Weight gain at 9 weeks isn’t just okay—it’s recommended. How much weight your doctor recommends you put on during pregnancy will depend on your pre-pregnancy body mass index (BMI). For example, if you started out with an average BMI, you will likely be told to put on a total of 25 to 35 pounds total during pregnancy—about three to five pounds of that should happen in the first trimester. If you’re 9 weeks pregnant with twins, you should aim to put on about a pound per week right now.
            That said, so many moms-to-be are riddled with morning sickness and food aversions when they’re 9 weeks pregnant that they might not be gaining weight—they may be losing it! Naturally, you’ll want to talk to your OB about any concerns you have with your weight gain or loss—and definitely let him or her know if it’s sudden or drastic. But most doctors will tell you that minor weight loss is okay at this stage of the game. Once you begin getting your appetite back, you’ll have an opportunity to get your weight gain back on track.
            There are also pregnant women who get nausea so severe they need medical treatment. Hyperemesis gravidarum (HG) is diagnosed when a pregnant woman is so sick she’s dangerously dehydrated. If you can’t seem to keep any liquids down, are losing a significant amount of weight, or if you’ve fainted, you should tell your doctor, who will do a physical exam to see if you have HG.
            The good news is that there are treatments for HG. You may need an IV to replenish your fluids, and you and your doctor may choose to try a prescription anti-nausea medication to help stop the vomiting.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Buy a great maternity bra – thank us later,2.Estimate your prenatal and delivery costs,3.Get trusted answers to early pregnancy questions,</checklist>
    </week9>

    <week10>
        <description>Hello baby bump! Now that you’ve reached 10 weeks pregnant, you may stop wondering when you’ll start to actually look pregnant, because it’s probably right around now! That’s why week 10 is a good time for a little retail therapy. While you shop, stock up on some new, looser clothes—and maybe your first round of maternity wear. Don’t go too crazy at the store though. As your body continues to change, you’ll want to pick up some more essentials along the way. Remember, you’ve still got seven more months of body changes.
            How Big Is Baby at 10 Weeks?
            During week 10 of pregnancy, baby is as big as a strawberry, measuring about 1.2 inches long and weighing about .14 ounces. Your 10-week baby’s body length will almost double in the next three weeks. Wow!
            10 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            At 10 weeks pregnant, you’re about two months and one week pregnant.</description>
        <symptoms>Wondering what to expect at 10 weeks pregnant? As baby grows, your ligaments and muscles are starting to stretch inside your 10 weeks pregnant belly, your breasts are getting bigger, and some other radical changes may be happening. Here are some of the most common 10 weeks pregnant symptoms:
            Round ligament pain. Don’t be surprised if you start feeling some aches and pains in your abdomen as it stretches to accommodate your growing baby. While some moms-to-be don’t really get or notice them, others find these sensations—called “round ligament pain”— well, downright painful. If you’re 10 weeks pregnant with twins, round ligament pain could be even more noticeable. Let your OB know if your discomfort is intense or if you’re worried in any way about your 10 weeks pregnant symptoms.
            Growing breasts. Your breasts have probably gotten bigger by week 10 of pregnancy, since they’ve been prepping for breastfeeding for weeks already!
            Morning sickness. Nausea and vomiting are pretty common at 10 weeks pregnant. The good news is, they’ll likely subside soon after you hit the second trimester.
            Mood swings. Changes in your hormones may be to blame for a roller coaster of emotions.
            Fatigue. You’re zapped. Here’s why: Not only is your body working really hard to grow baby, but your sleep might be disrupted by some pretty weird dreams.
            Increased vaginal discharge. An increased blood flow to your vagina coupled with an increase in estrogen production could cause more of a clear, odorless discharge called leukorrhea. Might seem a little gross, but this substance is simply nature’s way of getting rid of bacteria. If it’s colored, tinged with blood, has a foul odor, or causes discomfort, however, call your doctor. Those could be something else.
            Visible veins. Those blue streaks serve an important purpose: They’re carrying a ton of extra blood to baby.</symptoms>
        <belly>Your 10 weeks pregnant belly is probably just starting to show. That’s because your baby is continuing his or her rapid growth and so your tummy has started to develop some extra curve. You still might not look pregnant to people you meet, but you might need some pants with a stretchy waistband and some loose-fitting tops right around 10 weeks pregnant.
            Many doctors recommend gaining about three to five pounds during the first trimester for pregnant women of average BMI. So you’re right on track if you find yourself at 10 weeks pregnant having gained a few pounds.
            If you’re pregnant with twins, your doctor may recommend you gain about a pound per week in the first half of your pregnancy, which means you could have gained about 10 pounds by the time you’ve reached 10 weeks pregnant with twins. But don’t worry if you haven’t gained that much weight, or even if you’ve lost weight due to morning sickness. You’ll hopefully be able to put weight back on during the second trimester when the nausea decreases.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Schedule your CVS test,2.Schedule your nuchal translucency screening,3.Get the DL on exercise dos and dont's,</checklist>
    </week10>

    <week11>
        <description>Get on Airbnb and Trip Advisor, stat! Pregnancy week 11 is a great time to start planning a babymoon: a romantic getaway with your partner. We recommend you go on this trip in the second trimester, since that’s when you’ll feel most energized, and we doubt you’ll want to do a lot of traveling once you hit the third trimester. A babymoon isn’t just a cool way to celebrate your pregnancy; it’s a chance to bond with your partner before baby starts taking up a ton of your time and attention. Hey, maybe you’ll get to relax a little too! So, take your mind off your queasiness and start scouting some babymoon destinations now, at week 11 of your pregnancy. And if you need another diversion, imagine your growing baby, doing just fine in there, becoming more developed every day.
            How Big Is a Baby at 11 Weeks?
            Baby is now as big as a lime! Your 11-week fetus is about 1.6 inches long and weighs in at about .25 ounces. He or she's got about a 1:1 head-to-body ratio (which sounds weird, but that will change!).
            11 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            When you are 11 weeks, you are two months and about two weeks pregnant. In another couple of weeks, you’ll begin the second trimester.</description>
        <symptoms>Around 11 weeks, your body (and mind!) are still completely haywire. It’s probably tough to feel calm right now, since your hormones are still raging and you may still be feeling pretty nauseous. But know there’s light at the end of the tunnel—just a couple more weeks left in the first trimester, which is notoriously the worst for pregnancy symptoms! Here’s more about what you’re likely feeling at 11 weeks pregnant:

            Fatigue. You’re beat, but you can expect a surge in your energy in trimester two. Until then, give yourself permission to kick back and get some extra rest.
            Nausea. We get it. You’re sick and tired of being sick and tired. We promise you should start to feel more like yourself soon.
            Gas (oof!). Sorry, but tummy troubles are par for the pregnancy course. Keep a close eye on your diet (if you’re able to hold anything down, that is) and try to avoid foods that make you gassy, such as beans, cabbage, fried foods, and desserts. Drink lots of liquids and fiber-rich foods too.
            Mood swings. Try some mind/body exercises, like yoga, to help you feel more Zen. And if possible, avoid stressful situations (like that crowded family party—stay home with Netflix!).
            Leg cramps. Tight, painful muscles can strike at night and interfere with your sleep. Drinking plenty of water can prevent leg cramps, and so can stretching your legs during the day. You also want to take a look at your diet to be sure you’re getting enough potassium and magnesium.
            Skin darkening. One morning you might wake and think, Whoa! What’s that dark line down the center my belly and why is it there? Well, this is a totally normal pregnancy symptom called the linea nigra. This dark line is caused by hormonal changes and isn’t permanent—though you might notice that it sticks around for a while after you give birth, especially if you breastfeed. (Because of the hormones involved with breastfeeding.)
            Vaginal discharge. Okay, so you’re probably going to want to invest in some pantiliners, because an increase in discharge can be expected through your pregnancy.
            Women who are 11 weeks pregnant with twins often have elevated hormone levels, which may mean double the symptoms and higher weight gain. Both are normal, and you too should experience increased energy and decreased nausea in the coming weeks.</symptoms>
        <belly>Your 11 weeks pregnant belly is starting to develop a full-on baby bump instead of just gas and bloating, but it can be hard to tell! Especially if it’s your first pregnancy, you might not be showing at 11 weeks. Women pregnant with their second babies and those who are 11 weeks pregnant with twins tend to start showing earlier than first-time moms-to-be.
            While your belly may or may not be visibly changing, you may be surprised to see your boobs have noticeably changed. (Which may be welcome or unwelcome, depending on your preference!) We recommend you shop for some new, comfy, stretchy bras at this stage in the game. If you’re planning on breastfeeding, a nursing bra can be worn now and will come in handy after baby’s born. Plus, nursing bras are normally made to keep up with a changing bust size, and you probably have some more growing to do.
            At 11 weeks, the chance of miscarriage might be on your mind. It’s tough not to worry—welcome to motherhood!—but know now that you’ve seen baby’s heartbeat, your miscarriage risk is down to just 3 percent. It will drop even lower over the next month or so.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Shop for stylish maternity clothes,2.Plan a babymoon,3.Start your baby registry,</checklist>
    </week11>

    <week12>
        <description>Things are changing fast at 12 weeks pregnant. You’re reaching the home stretch of the first trimester (we know, finally!), which means your hormones are likely to tone things down a bit—hopefully making you feel fewer pregnancy symptoms. It also means you may be ready to share your pregnancy news with family and friends. So exciting!
            How Big Is Baby at 12 Weeks?
            At 12 weeks pregnant, baby is as big as a plum. The average fetus at 12 weeks is about 2.1 inches long and .49 ounces. Now that baby's got pretty much all his or her important organs, his or her main job is to keep on growing. Go, baby go!
            12 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            At twelve weeks pregnant, you’re in the last week of your third month of pregnancy. In other words, you’ll be three months pregnant around the end of week 12 of your pregnancy.</description>
        <symptoms>Here’s the good news about 12 weeks pregnant symptoms: morning sickness and fatigue may start to fade a bit soon, as your hormones start to calm down. The bad? Headaches and dizziness may replace them. We’ll take that trade-off. Here’s more info about what’s happening to your body at 12 weeks pregnant:
            Increased discharge. This clear discharge might seem weird, but it’s normal and has an important purpose: to protect your vagina from infection. But if you have yellow, greenish, pink, or brown discharge during pregnancy week 12, call your doctor right away. Those colors could be a sign of infection or preterm labor.
            Spotting. Spotting or bleeding during pregnancy at 12 weeks could be worrisome—or it could be nothing at all. For example, your cervix is more sensitive during pregnancy, so simply having sex could cause light bleeding that’s harmless. If you’re spotting or bleeding, definitely tell your doctor. If the bleeding is accompanied by cramping or the flow is heavy, it’s an urgent call.
            Headaches. These may start to intensify around week 12 of pregnancy. Headaches may be caused by hormonal shifts, drops in blood sugar, dehydration, lack of sleep, or stress. To deal, pay attention to what might be triggering your headaches and try to avoid those culprits. If you notice a drastic increase in headaches or a type of headache you’ve never experienced before (such as a migraine), or if your headaches are accompanied by other weird symptoms, let your OB know.
            Dizziness. Whoa! Hormone shifts and blood pressure changes could cause dizzy spells around pregnancy week 12. You can help prevent dizziness by snacking regularly and drinking plenty of water. Sit or lie down if you’re feeling dizzy or lightheaded and let your doc know about any severe bouts.
            If you’re 12 weeks pregnant with twins, you may still be experiencing morning sickness, while your singleton mom-to-be counterparts are likely starting to see the light at the end of the nausea tunnel. Know that things will likely improve soon.
        </symptoms>
        <belly>A 12 weeks, your pregnant belly is an official bump! In other words, it’s probably getting noticeable now. This is one reason many moms-to-be start to tell others they’re expecting around 12 weeks. (Of course, if you’re 12 weeks pregnant with twins, you may have been showing for weeks now, obviously because you’ve got double the baby in there!)
            If you haven’t already, start taking photos of your pregnant belly at 12 weeks. Trust us, after pregnancy you’ll want a memento of how much your body changed throughout the nine months.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Schedule your 16-week prenatal visit,2.Stock up on pregnancy food for baby,3.Share your news with friends and family,</checklist>
    </week12>

    <week13>
        <description>Congrats! You’ve made it through the first trimester! We’re not just talking about getting through those work meetings without falling asleep (or puking!), we’re talking about how you’re now 1/3rd of the way through your pregnancy! At 13 weeks pregnant, you’ve grown a fetus that has vocal cords, teeth, and even fingerprints (wow!) and you’ve probably kept this incredible news (mostly) secret while wishing you could shout it from the rooftops—or, at the very least, use it as an excuse for getting to work late.
            Around week 13 of pregnancy, many parents-to-be start spreading the word that there’s a baby on the way. But know that there are no hard-and-fast rules about when you should divulge your secret. It could be after your next prenatal appointment, once you start showing, or at a big family event where everyone will be gathered. Or maybe everyone already knows! That’s totally your call.
            How Big Is Baby at 13 Weeks?
            At 13 weeks pregnant, baby is as big as a lemon. Your 13-week fetus is about 2.9 inches long and weighs about .81 ounces, and proportion-wise, his or her head is now about 1/3 the size of the body instead of ½.
            13 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            13 weeks pregnant is 3 months pregnant. This is the last week of the first trimester. (We can’t say it enough because it’s so great to be here!)</description>
        <symptoms>You might notice that around 13 weeks pregnant, your symptoms change a bit. You might actually be able to get through the day without nausea (if not now, soon) or feeling the need for a nap. But you may be experiencing a few of these too:
            Visible veins. You can see all those blue streaks under your skin because you have increased blood flow.
            Increase in energy. The second trimester is known as the least symptomatic—and the most energetic. As you start to feel more like yourself and get that energy surge, you’re going to want to knock a bunch of to-dos off your list. Also, if you’ve found yourself too sick and tired to exercise lately, now’s the time to get back to a fitness routine. Exercise will only benefit you and baby and can even make labor easier. Worth it!
            Increased sex drive. If you’re one of those lucky pregnant women who feels up for a roll in the hay at 13 weeks, well… enjoy! You may notice a bit of post-coital spotting during pregnancy at 13 weeks. A little spotting is normal simply because your cervix is more sensitive. But heavy bleeding (like a period) isn’t, so call your doctor if it’s more like a flow.
            Sorry, twin moms-to-be. If you’re 13 weeks pregnant with twins, you might still be experiencing some morning sickness and fatigue. That’s because twin moms can have more of the pregnancy hormone hCG in their systems. If your nausea and vomiting is super severe, definitely bring it up to your OB. If you’re able to hold down food and liquids, but you’re still feeling ill, just wait it out a little longer.</symptoms>
        <belly>Your uterus is now big enough that it’s growing up and out of your pelvis. That means you’re starting to actually look pregnant. Finally, right? You’re a third of the way through and you finally get to demand a seat on a crowded train!
            Expect to look more and more pregnant from here on out because pregnancy at 13 weeks calls for a weight gain increase. OBs recommend you gain weight in the healthiest way possible—that means slowly and steadily throughout your pregnancy. Here are the weight gain guidelines outlined by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists (ACOG):
            If you’re underweight (BMI under 18.5):
            Your recommended total pregnancy weight gain is 28 to 40 pounds.
            In the second and third trimesters, aim to gain about a pound (1 to 1.3 pounds to be exact) per week.
            If you’re average weight (BMI of 18.5 to 24.9):
            Your recommended total pregnancy weight gain is 25 to 35 pounds.
            In the second and third trimesters, aim to gain about a pound or a little less (0.8 to 1 pound to be exact) per week.
            If you’re overweight (BMI of 25 to 29.9):
            Your recommended total pregnancy weight gain is 15 to 25 pounds.
            In the second and third trimesters, aim to gain a little over a half pound (0.5 to 0.7 pounds to be exact) per week.
            If you’re obese (BMI of 30 and above):
            Your recommended total pregnancy weight gain is 11 to 20 pounds.
            In the second and third trimesters, aim to gain about a half pound (0.4 to 0.6 pounds to be exact) per week.
            If you’re 13 weeks pregnant with twins:
            Your recommended total pregnancy weight gain is 37 to 54 pounds.
            In the first half of your pregnancy, aim to gain about a pound per week. In the second half, aim to gain a little over a pound per week.
            Of course, you don’t want to stress yourself out about these numbers. What’s important is that you’re eating a healthy diet full of a variety of different foods, eating about 300 extra (nutritious) calories per day more than you did pre-pregnancy and getting plenty of exercise.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Tell your boss you're pregnant,2.Prepare your child for the new baby,3.Start thinking about child care for baby,4.Change up your pregnancy workout,</checklist>
    </week13>

    <week14>
        <description>Welcome to the second trimester! 14 weeks pregnant marks a lot of changes—you might be feeling less nauseated, hungrier, and more energetic. That’s because you’re embarking on what’s known as the “honeymoon phase” of pregnancy. Starting with pregnancy week 14, the second trimester is the time to get some exercise, get some to-do’s done, and have some fun. Enjoy!
            How Big Is Baby at 14 Weeks?
            At 14 weeks pregnant, baby is as big as a peach, measuring 3.4 inches and weighing in at 1.5 ounces. Baby has almost doubled in weight since last week, and keeps on growing at super speed at week 14.
            14 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            14 weeks pregnant means you’re about three months and one week pregnant. You’re at the beginning of your second trimester.</description>
        <symptoms>At 14 weeks pregnant, symptoms you felt in the first trimester might be fading. But don’t be surprised if they don’t vanish right away. Be patient and take it easy! Here are some new pregnancy symptoms you may be feeling at 14 weeks:
            Round ligament pain. Yowch! You're probably feeling some aches and pains as your muscles and ligaments stretch to accommodate your growing baby. At 14 weeks pregnant, cramps are often because of round ligament pain, but if you have any concerns, talk to your doctor.
            Increased energy. As you emerge from the nasties of the first trimester, you're probably getting your energy back. #ThankGoodness
            Increased appetite. Tummy’s rumbling? Once morning sickness starts to go away, you might find your appetite on overdrive. Remember that what you eat is fueling baby’s rapid growth. You should aim to eat about 300 extra calories per day. If you’re 14 weeks pregnant with twins, you’ll want to eat about 680 extra calories per day now that you’re in your second trimester. Keep plenty of healthy snacks by your side just in case you get the munchies. It’s important—for you and for baby—that you don’t indulge in too many greasy, fatty foods, so you’re both getting the right nutrients. (Of course, the occasional bowl of ice cream is totally okay.)
            Thicker, shinier hair. You might notice your hair getting thicker and shinier, one of the (few) attractive side effects of pregnancy.</symptoms>
        <belly>Your 14-week pregnant belly might be feeling achy and sore, but that’s simply because your uterus is expanding to accommodate your rapidly growing baby.
            Don’t be surprised if weight gain starts to speed up at 14 weeks pregnant. If you started out at an average BMI, doctors recommend you gain about one to two pounds per week starting at 14 weeks pregnant. If you’re 14 weeks pregnant with twins, your weight gain goal will be about the same as singleton moms until week 20 when you should start gaining a bit more. Of course, if you started out underweight or with a high BMI—or if you lost or gained a significant amount of weight in the first trimester—your doctor might recommend a slightly different weight gain goal.
            If you found yourself shying away from exercise during trimester one, now that you have your energy back, it’s time to get back on track. Consider taking a prenatal yoga class or simply get that 14 weeks pregnant belly out for a walk!</belly>
        <checklist>1.See the dentist,2.See fun ways to announce your pregnancy,3.Research and sign up for a childbirth class,</checklist>
    </week14>

    <week15>
        <description>Now that you’re at 15 weeks pregnant, you’re probably feeling very high energy, and that may mean high libido too. Your partner isn’t feeling nearly as frisky at week 15 pregnancy? That’s normal too. Let’s face it, the thought of baby being so close while you two are, um, doing the deed, can freak him out. Remind your partner that baby has no idea what’s going on—and, as long as your OB hasn’t given you any activity restrictions—sex won’t hurt baby or threaten your pregnancy.
            How Big Is a Baby at 15 Weeks Pregnant?
            At 15 weeks pregnant, baby is as big as a navel orange. The average 15-week fetus weighs 2.5 ounces and measures 4 inches—and baby's proportions are becoming even more normal, since his or her legs now out-measure the arms.
            15 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            15 weeks pregnant is three months and approximately two weeks pregnant.</description>
        <symptoms>Are your 15 weeks pregnant symptoms hot… or not? Here’s a bit of what you might be experiencing, from sexy (increased libido) to not-so-sexy (nosebleeds and stomach issues) at week 15 pregnancy.
            Increased sex drive. Now that your energy is back, you may be feeling more energetic in the bedroom as well. Of course, with all the other 15 weeks pregnant symptoms you may be feeling, if you’re not up to sex, it’s completely understandable.
            Nosebleeds. This not-so-lovely symptom is thanks to a combination of increased blood volume and sensitive nasal passages.
            Heartburn, gas and/or indigestion. Blame these tummy troubles on the hormones. Pay attention to foods that are triggering your symptoms and try to avoid them. Also, talk to your doctor about what stomach remedies are safe. Stock up on some antacids, which are doubly awesome because they have lots of much-needed calcium!
            Swollen gums. Your gums are more sensitive now that you’re pregnant. Take extra good care of them. Brush your teeth often, floss gently, and see your dentist for regular checkups.
            Shortness of breath. Notice that you’re easily winded? Let’s face it; it’s getting more crowded in your torso. That means it might be trickier for your lungs to expand enough to get a full breath.
            If you’re 15 weeks pregnant with twins, your symptoms probably aren’t much different than they would be for a mom carrying one baby at 15 weeks. However, because higher hormone levels in trimester one may have made you more likely to have morning sickness, you may still be having bouts of nausea, which should begin to lessen soon. Let your OB know if you have any severe or concerning symptoms.</symptoms>
        <belly>Your 15 weeks pregnant belly is making a big transition. During the first trimester, your uterus still fit nicely inside your pelvis. But now, it’s stretching to accommodate your growing baby and will soon outgrow your pelvis and sit higher up in your belly. Every mom-to-be’s body is different, and the rate of growth can vary slightly. That’s why at week 15 of pregnancy, it’s completely normal to not show much, or have an obvious baby bump. For example, a 15 weeks pregnant belly for a first pregnancy could take a little longer to begin to stick out. For the second pregnancy and beyond, the uterus has already been stretched, so you might have a bump a little earlier in repeat pregnancies.
            If you’re 15 weeks pregnant with twins, things are probably stretching out at a faster rate, and you’re likely showing by now. Step away from the Doritos! Recommended 15 weeks pregnant weight gain is about 1 to 2 pounds per week, so continue to eat about 300 extra calories per day—and try to make them healthy calories whenever possible. If you notice drastic or sudden weight gain, notify your doctor right away. This could be a sign of a serious pregnancy condition called preeclampsia.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Schedule your multiple marker screening,2.Schedule your amnio (if you're having one),3.Pamper yourself,</checklist>
    </week15>

    <week16>
        <description>Now that you’re 16 weeks pregnant, things are getting pretty exciting. You may have another prenatal visit this week, where you will get to hear baby’s heartbeat again. Even more thrilling will be feeling baby kick, which could happen starting this week, so pay attention to those subtle feelings in your 16 weeks pregnant belly. Another cool fact? Baby’s starting to be able to hear your voice—and he or she will recognize it at birth—so feel free to chat baby up any chance you get.
            How Big Is Baby at 16 Weeks Pregnant?
            At 16 weeks pregnant, baby is the size of an avocado, measuring 4.6 inches long and weighing in at 3.5 ounces.
            16 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            16 weeks pregnant is three months and about three weeks pregnant.</description>
        <symptoms>More reason to celebrate: There are some 16 weeks pregnant symptoms that are actually good. For example, some moms-to-be find their hair and nails grow faster. Your hair might actually look thicker and more lustrous and your skin might look radiant, too. Woo hoo! Here’s more of what you might be feeling at 16 weeks pregnant:
            Backaches. Your aching back is a side effect of pregnancy hormones. To ease backaches, make some time for low-impact exercise. Sit and stand up straight and regularly stretch your body.
            Bigger boobs. Your breasts have probably gone up several cup sizes by now, and should be completely prepped for breastfeeding by the end of the second trimester.
            Constipation. Getting, um, stopped up is an unfortunate result of your uterus starting to press on your intestines. Load up on fiber-rich foods and drink lots of water to keep things moving.
            Forgetfulness. This is also known as #PregnancyBrain. No one knows for sure what causes pregnant women to become more forgetful. It could be biological or it just could be a result of having lots on your mind!
            Dry, itchy, sensitive eyes. Blame the hormones once again! You could try over-the-counter eye drops, but be sure to consult your OB before choosing one.
            Glowing skin. Finally—that pregnancy glow that people are always talking about. Va va voom!
            If you’re sixteen weeks pregnant with twins, your symptoms probably won’t be different than they would be for a mom carrying one baby at this point. You definitely want to keep your doctor posted on all your symptoms though, since a twin pregnancy is considered higher risk, so your doctor will want to keep close tabs on you and your babies.</symptoms>
        <belly>Pretty soon, you’ll start feeling baby moving around in your 16 weeks pregnant belly. At first, those moves might feel like gas or a muscle twitch, but over time, as baby gets bigger and stronger, they’ll be unmistakable. If you’re 16 weeks pregnant with twins, you won’t feel kicks any earlier than a singleton mom-to-be will, but over time, twin moms definitely feel more kicking sensations.
            Of course, feeling those movements comes with other issues, like having your lungs crowded by your growing babe. That could make it seem tough to catch your breath from time to time.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Schedule your 20-week prenatal visit,2.Schedule your mid-pregnancy ultrasound,3.Start a baby name list (if you haven't already!),</checklist>
    </week16>

    <week17>
        <description>Decisions, decisions. Now that you’re 17 weeks pregnant, start making firm plans, like whether or not you’re going to find out baby’s gender (you should be able to soon!), and what kind of childbirth class you’d like to take. As you start making these decisions, the pregnancy will feel even more real, which is super exciting, but part of you is probably feeling a little anxious too. After all, you’re at week 17 of your pregnancy; that’s almost halfway through and there’s so much to do, it can be overwhelming. Our best advice? Don’t try to do it all yourself—ask for help. And whatever doesn’t get done? You’ll find it’s not that important anyhow.
            How Big Is Baby at 17 Weeks?
            A baby at pregnancy week 17 is the size of a pomegranate. Your 17-week fetus is about 5.1 inches long and weighs about 5.9 ounces.
            17 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            At 17 weeks pregnant, you’re three months and about three weeks pregnant. By the end of the week, you’ll officially be four months pregnant. Woot!</description>
        <symptoms>When you’re 17 weeks pregnant, symptoms are most commonly due to your rapidly growing baby. Here’s what you’re likely feeling this week:
            Increased bodily fluids. Vaginal discharge, sweat, mucus, and other fluids are in full force because of your increased blood flow.
            Weird dreams. You gave birth to a chipmunk? Married your boss? Having strange dreams might be caused by your hormones, but it might also be the result of your nerves and anticipation.
            Itchy boobs and belly. As baby's growing, your skin is stretching thinner and can be more sensitive. Resist the urge to scratch, and find a soothing skin cream that eases the itch. (We like Belly All Day Moisture Body Lotion.)
            More rapid weight gain. You may have gained about 5 to 10 pounds by now. It’s normal to gain about 1 to 2 pounds per week in the second trimester. Sudden or excessive weight gain could be a sign of a problem though, so talk to your OB if it’s higher than that.
            Stretch marks. As you’re putting on some pounds and your uterus continues to expand—we hate to break it to you—getting some stretch marks might be inevitable. (Especially if you’re 17 weeks pregnant with twins!) Drink lots of water to stay hydrated and use a good quality moisturizer to try to combat them.</symptoms>
        <belly>Baby’s working on getting stronger, and your 17 weeks pregnant body’s working on getting bigger—about one to two pounds bigger per week. (Weight gain should be about the same if you’re 17 weeks pregnant with twins.) Make sure you document your growing 17 weeks pregnant belly by taking lots of photos. We promise: one day you’re going to look back and reminisce about this time. You’ll want to have a keepsake of how your body changed.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Decision point: Will you find out baby's gender?,2.Get nursery inspiration,3.Plan your maternity leave,</checklist>
    </week17>

    <week18>
        <description>Time to switch things up. Starting around 18 weeks pregnant you should begin to sleep on your side instead of your back. That’s because baby (and your uterus) is getting big enough to press against large veins in the back of your abdomen, which can reduce the amount of blood going to your heart, making you feel lightheaded—or worse, lowering your blood pressure. Sounds scary, but it’s totally preventable by simply sleeping on your side. Of course, your veins aren’t the only things that are prone to pressure—you are too! At pregnancy week 18, there’s a lot going on. Be sure, in your hectic schedule, that you plan some time to take breaks and unwind. Great excuse for a date night or a prenatal massage!
            18 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            At 18 weeks, you’re officially four months pregnant. Only five more months to go!
            How Big Is Baby at 18 Weeks?
            At 18 weeks pregnant, baby is as big as an artichoke. Baby's about 5.6 inches long and about 6.7 ounces now and keeps growing quickly. That's why you're probably feeling so hungry!</description>
        <symptoms>Not only are you super busy preparing for baby, but you might be having some not-so-fun 18 weeks pregnant symptoms, like swollen feet or hands, backaches, leg cramps, and nosebleeds. And the stress and discomfort can keep you up at night around week 18 of pregnancy. Here’s the scoop on the 18 weeks pregnant symptoms you may be feeling:
            Swollen feet and/or hands. Swelling can be an annoying pregnancy symptom. It’s nothing to worry about as long as the swelling isn't sudden or severe. If it is, tell your doctor right away.
            Backaches. Baby's putting a lot of pressure on your insides, causing aches and pains in your back.
            Leg cramps. Cramps can be a sign of dehydration, so drink up!
            Varicose veins. These visible purple or blue veins are swollen due to all that extra pressure on your circulatory system. To deal with them, change positions often, prop your legs up when you can, get plenty of exercise, and avoid tight clothes and shoes.
            Trouble sleeping. Your mind is working overtime and you're getting more and more uncomfortable. This can wreak havoc on your ability to catch the Zs you need.
            Nosebleeds. Bet you never expected these! Increased pressure on the veins in your nose may be making it bleed more than usual. If you have a nosebleed, apply pressure by pinching your nose for five to ten minutes. An ice pack can also help stop the bleeding.
            Baby kicks. Whether you’re 18 weeks pregnant with twins, triplets, or a single baby, you’re probably feeling not just tiny flutters but more definitive sensations resembling actual kicks. They’re getting stronger!</symptoms>
        <belly>Your 18 weeks pregnant belly is rapidly expanding—all the stretching and pressure it’s causing are what’s causing those symptoms.
            Weight gain at 18 weeks pregnant is recommended to be about 1 to 2 pounds per week for women of average BMI, whether you’re having one baby or you’re 18 weeks pregnant with twins. Let your doctor know if you have any concerns with your weight gain so far. Drastic or sudden weight gain or weight loss could be signs of a problem.
            If you’re 18 weeks pregnant and not showing much, everything’s probably A-OK. Remember: Every pregnant body is different, and your uterus will grow up and out of your pelvis at a slightly different time as another pregnant woman’s does.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Read up on baby care,2.Plan a date night with your partner,3.Switch your sleep position from back to side,</checklist>
    </week18>

    <week19>
        <description>So what do you think: is it a boy or a girl? At 19 weeks pregnant, you’re probably getting psyched for your mid-pregnancy ultrasound. Most parents-to-be think of this test as the chance to find out baby’s gender, but you will actually see a lot more than baby’s boy or girl parts. You’ll see all of baby’s body—inside and out—and you’ll be amazed at all the development going on in there at week 19 of pregnancy. That’s exciting!
            How Big Is Baby at 19 Weeks?
            Baby is as big as a mango at 19 weeks of pregnancy. At about 6.0 inches long and weighing in at about 8.5 ounces, your 19-week fetus continues to get bigger!
            19 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            19 weeks pregnant is four months and about one week pregnant. In another week, you’ll be halfway through. Can you believe it?</description>
        <symptoms>Normal 19-weeks pregnant symptoms aren’t severe—they’re more like annoyances. Of course, that doesn’t mean that dealing with them is easy. These are a few of the not-so-fun symptoms you may be feeling at 19 weeks:
            Abdominal aches and pains. Round ligament pain is that discomfort in your lower 19-week pregnant belly. It’s caused by your muscles stretching to accommodate baby. Let your OB know if any ache or pain concerns you, but as long it’s not intense or accompanied by other symptoms, these are just growing pains.
            Dizziness or lightheadedness. Feeling faint? We’ve been witness to more than one pregnant woman passing out—if it happens to you, know you’re not alone. Lightheadedness during pregnancy can happen because your growing uterus puts pressure on your blood vessels. Plus, baby is crowding your lungs, so there’s less oxygen for you! But there are other things that contribute to lightheadedness, including dehydration and hunger, so take care of yourself and eat and drink regularly! If you find yourself getting dizzy or lightheaded often, your OB may want to check you for anemia and/or preeclampsia.
            Leg cramps. Ugh—we feel your pain! One way to ease these ouchies: stretching. Extend your leg and flex your ankle and toes toward your knees. (Some prenatal yoga might help too.) Or enlist your partner for a calf (and back!) massage.
            Hip pain. If hip pain bothers you at night, try sleeping on your side with a pillow between your knees. Those giant body pillows might seem big and dorky, but we can’t sing the praises of them enough—especially if you’re 19 weeks pregnant with twins. Cave in and get one.</symptoms>
        <belly>Whoa! Did you feel that? At 19 weeks pregnant, baby’s movement inside your belly is probably becoming noticeable to you. Of course, like with showing, this phenomenon happens earlier for some women than it does for others. Right now, these tiny movements probably feel more like taps or flutters—or even gas—but they’ll grow stronger over the next few weeks. Of course, it will be a bit more time before your partner or anyone else can feel those kicks. Until then, enjoy this little thing that’s just between you and baby. You two are bonding already.
            At 19 weeks pregnant, weight gain might start to concern you, since you’ve probably put on between 8 and 14 pounds so far. (Or 20 to 30 pounds, if you’re 19 weeks pregnant with twins.) If your weight gain to date is higher or lower than that, talk to your doctor about whether or not it’s cause for concern. Sudden or rapid weight gain could be a sign of preeclampsia—which needs to be treated ASAP—and inability to gain weight could mean that baby’s not getting enough nutrients.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Start interviewing pediatricians,2.Research cord blood banking,3.Sign up for an infant CPR class,</checklist>
    </week19>

    <week20>
        <description>Congrats! During week 20 of pregnancy, you’re at the halfway point. If you’ve recently found out baby’s sex, you’re in a completely new mindset—are we right? Now, those baby names you’re throwing out are more likely to end up as baby’s actual name, and when you find yourself in a baby store, those little blue or pink outfits aren’t just adorable, they’re must-haves. And since now you can add clothes and other boyish or girlish things to your wish list, 20 weeks pregnant is the time you probably want to start finalizing your baby registry too. Happy shopping!
            How Big Is Baby at 20 Weeks?
            At 20 weeks pregnant, baby is the size of a banana. He or she weighs about 10.2 ounces and measures about 6.5 inches from crown to rump. (Starting next week, baby will be measured from head to toe.) Baby's still got a lot of growing to do but has an excellent start!
            20 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            20 weeks pregnant is four months and about two weeks. During week 20, you’ve hit the halfway point of your pregnancy.</description>
        <symptoms>Making it to 20 weeks pregnant probably feels pretty darn good. After all, your energy’s high, your sex drive is high, and as long as your partner is up for it too, things are probably happening between the sheets. Of course, it wouldn’t be pregnancy if you weren’t experiencing some annoying symptoms. Right now, it’s likely swelling, heartburn, leg cramps, and more of this not-so-fun stuff:
            Vaginal discharge. You can expect the discharge to keep increasing until delivery. It’s just your body’s way of keeping the area clear of bacteria. But let your doctor know if the discharge is yellow, green, or foul smelling.
            Leg cramps. Do stretches regularly, and drink plenty of water to prevent your legs from cramping.
            Heartburn and/or indigestion. As baby starts to crowd your digestive system, it might not work exactly as it did pre-pregnancy. Watch what you’re eating—acidic and spicy foods can cause tummy troubles.
            High energy. Enjoy this energy (and libido) surge while it lasts! You might find yourself more fatigued in the third trimester.
            Swelling. Don't worry unless the swelling is sudden or severe. Mild swelling is normal and should subside after delivery. In the meantime, put up your feet whenever you can.
            Shortness of breath. As your uterus expands, it pushes against your lungs, causing you to feel short of breath. You might find this to be especially true if you’re 20 weeks pregnant with twins. Don’t push yourself too hard, and sit down and rest if you feel yourself gasping for air.</symptoms>
        <belly>Starting around 20 weeks pregnant, your doctor will measure fundal height at each prenatal visit. Fundal height is the distance from the pubic bone to the top of your uterus. In centimeters, the fundal height should match your week of pregnancy, give or take two centimeters. So for example, your 20 weeks pregnant belly should measure around 18 to 22 centimeters. It should continue to increase about a centimeter each week. A higher or lower fundal height could be the sign of a pregnancy condition such as gestational diabetes, a growth issue, or a breech baby, so if it doesn’t appear to be average, further testing may be necessary.
            At 20 weeks pregnant, weight gain is happening slowly yet surely. You may have gained around 10 pounds by now. Remember: You’re aiming to gain about 1 to 2 pounds per week.
            Recommended pregnancy weight gain for moms of average BMI is about 25 to 35 pounds. If you began pregnancy with a high BMI, your OB will likely advise that you gain a total of 15 to 25 pounds. If you were at a low BMI, 28 to 40 pounds will likely be the recommendation.
            If you’re 20 weeks pregnant with twins or other multiples, don’t expect your doctor to measure your fundal height. That’s because it’s harder to say what’s average for moms-to-be carrying multiples. Instead, your OB will likely put more emphasis on your weight gain. Now that you’re 20 weeks pregnant with twins, you should aim to put on slightly more weight each week. In the first half of a twin pregnancy, the recommendation is about 1 pound per week, and in the second half, it’s about one to two pounds. That’s because healthy weight gain is gradual. Most OBs advise that twin moms-to-be of average BMI gain about 35 to 45 pounds total during pregnancy.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Schedule your 24-week prenatal visit,2.Find out baby's gender,3.Make key baby registry decisions,</checklist>
    </week20>

    <week21>
        <description>Pressure’s on! Have you found the perfect baby name yet? It seems like parents-to-be either come up with baby’s name quickly and easily, or agonize over it all the way up until the birth. If you haven’t picked that perfect name yet, check out The Bump’s extensive lists of baby names of all sorts; cool names, beautiful names, hipster names, and much more. Whatever name you choose, you’ll probably think it’s even more perfect once you get to know (and fall in love with) your future little bundle of joy. At 21 weeks pregnant, you’re not just choosing a name, you’re hard at work getting your home ready too. Of course, things like baby bouncers and changing table pads can be tough to choose, but try not to stress about it at week 21 of pregnancy. Trust us, baby won’t care if you pick out a pack ‘n play that clashes with the area rug!
            How Big Is Baby at 21 Weeks?
            At 21 weeks pregnant, baby is as big as a head of endive. At 10.5 inches and about 12.7 ounces, baby's big enough now that you've probably been feeling his or her fetal movements more and more lately.
            21 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            21 weeks pregnant is 4 months and about three weeks. Now that you’re more than halfway done with month five, you’re a majority of the way through your pregnancy!</description>
        <symptoms>Common 21 weeks pregnant symptoms are kind of like a sneak preview of the third trimester. Here’s what you might be feeling at week 21 of pregnancy:
            Heartburn and/or indigestion. Avoid spicy and greasy foods and other triggers. If the source of your discomfort is a mystery, keeping a food diary could help you figure it out.
            Braxton Hicks contractions. Your uterus might occasionally feel tight as it practices for labor. This is totally normal as long as the contractions go away when you switch positions. Let your doctor know about any pain or contractions that don’t stop.
            Leaky boobs. Your milk ducts will be fully developed by the end of this trimester—just in case of an early arrival.
            Dry, itchy skin. Your skin is stretching over your growing bump, making it more irritated by the day. Lather up with a pregnancy-safe body oil or lotion to help your skin stay moisturized and hopefully less itchy. Also, if you develop a rash, let your doctor know right away, since that could be a sign of an annoying pregnancy condition called PUPPP.
            Stretch marks. Your skin gets pulled thinner as baby grows, causing tiny tears beneath the surface of your skin. Stretch marks are more common for some women simply because of family history, or because of sudden weight gain. They are also more common in women who are 21 weeks pregnant with twins. There’s no way to truly get rid of stretch marks, but they should fade significantly after birth.</symptoms>
        <belly>This week, you may look in the mirror and wonder, “Where did I go?!” By the time you reach 21 weeks pregnant, you may have gained around 13 to 14 pounds, and around 21 pounds if you’re 21 weeks pregnant with twins.
            Your newfound curves might have you feeling super sexy and confident—after all, you’re the center of attention wherever you go! But the extra weight also might have you feeling… fat. (You’re not—you’re pregnant!) Remind yourself, you’re supposed to be gaining this weight! It’s good for you and for baby.
            In fact, all the weight you gain during pregnancy isn’t just padding for baby—it all serves a really important purpose. Here’s a logical way to think of it: Of the approximately 30 pounds you’ll gain throughout your pregnancy, there’s a whole lot more than fat. Here’s what makes up that weight:
            An average full-term baby = 7.5 pounds
            Placenta = 1.5 pounds
            Uterus = 2 pounds
            Amniotic fluid = 2 pounds
            Maternal stores of fat, protein, and other nutrients (needed for breastfeeding!) = 7 pounds
            Breast tissue (also for BFing, of course) = 2 pounds
            Increased fluid volume = 4 pounds
            Increased blood volume = 4 pounds
            See? All those pounds are doing a lot of good, keeping baby alive and healthy—and storing up good stuff to nourish him or her after birth.
            Any time you’re feeling a little meh about your body, think of all the amazing things it’s doing! Now, at 21 weeks, fetal movement is noticeable—and baby has reflexes too! If you gently press your palm on your belly, you might feel a little push back. So cool!</belly>
        <checklist>1.Schedule your glucose challenge test,2.Start planning your baby shower,3.Narrow your list of baby names,</checklist>
    </week21>

    <week22>
        <description>It’s getting crowded in there! Now that you’re 22 weeks pregnant, your rapidly growing baby is invading your space—to say the least. That’s why it might be tough to catch your breath and why your back might be killing you. Hey, as baby grows, he or she may be expanding your belly so much (so fast) at week 22 of pregnancy that you might start to get some stretch marks (sorry)—and you might even have a newfound “outtie”! While you might not love all these side effects, you’ll probably want to capture your pregnant belly in some professional photos. 22 weeks is a good time to schedule a maternity portrait session. You’ll want to aim for a third trimester sesh to capture that big, beautiful belly, but it shouldn’t be so late that you risk going into labor before your appointment.
            How Big Is Baby at 22 Weeks?
            At 22 weeks, baby is the size of a coconut. Average baby size at 22 weeks is 10.9 inches long (from the crown of the head to the heel of the foot) and 15.2 ounces.
            22 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            Hmm… it’s becoming difficult to keep track, so what exactly is 22 weeks in months you ask? Answer is… you’re four months and about four weeks pregnant. Once week 22 of pregnancy ends, you’ll officially be five months pregnant.</description>
        <symptoms>The most common 22 weeks pregnant symptoms have to do with the fact that your baby (or babies, if you’re 22 weeks pregnant with twins) is taking over so much territory in your bod. This includes:
            Stretch marks. These scars are caused when your skin stretches so fast or so much that it actually tears below the surface. What’s not so cool is that the stretch marks may never go away completely, but they will fade in color after delivery, so they’ll be much less noticeable.
            Outtie belly button. Your innie has basically gone inside out and you’ve suddenly got an outtie. This is another byproduct of an expanding belly. It can be a weird feeling, we know. Your outtie will go back to an innie, we promise!
            Increased sex drive. Some moms-to-be actually find they have an increase in libido around 22 weeks. That’s because your hormones are pretty much raging at this point. (We hope you're enjoying it!)
            Increased vaginal discharge. You’ve got a water works situation down there—SO not fun, but don’t worry, it’s just the result of increased blood flow down there. This could be a reason not to feel the sex drive boost other moms-to-be get at this phase of the game, but we think you should try to get into the mood anyhow. We really doubt your partner will mind a little excess… um… lubrication.
            Swollen hands and/or feet. Now that you’re pregnant, you have an increase in the amount of fluids in your body. So minor swelling is totally normal and will die down pretty much as soon as baby is born. Severe or sudden swelling, on the other hand, is not normal. It could be a sign of a dangerous pregnancy complication called preeclampsia, so tell your OB right away if you’re super swollen or swollen with sudden onset.
            Backaches. Your back hurts due to extra pressure from baby and from carrying around the extra weight. A heating pad, a prenatal massage, and/or sleeping with a body pillow can help ease the pain.
            Hair growth. This is a pretty great symptom when the hair is… Actually. On. Your. Head. When it’s not on your head, well, go ahead and curse those hormones for the umpteenth time. (And break out the tweezers if you want!)
            Trouble catching your breath. Baby continues to crowd your lungs, making it tough to breathe at times. Remember not to take your workouts too far, and when you feel winded, take a break right away.</symptoms>
        <belly>A typical 22 weeks pregnant belly measures approximately 20 to 24 centimeters from pelvic bone to the top of the uterus—that’s called the “fundal height.” If you’re 22 weeks pregnant with twins, don’t even consider fundal height, since twin pregnancies are all so different, there’s no real “typical.”
            At 22 weeks pregnant, weight gain is likely on your mind. Your OB is probably telling you to stick to a slow and steady weight gain—about a pound or slightly more or less per week, depending on your body type. To do that, many people advise eating about 300 extra calories per day. Don’t obsess over calorie counting or anything—it’s just a good guideline to keep in mind.
            300 extra calories doesn’t mean you have to eat exactly three meals, plus one or two small snacks. In fact, you should consider switching it up and eating five or six small meals over the course of your day. That way, it might be easier to stick to a well-rounded diet (since, admit it, most of us make healthier choices with our meals than we do with our snacks). Plus, by eating smaller meals and more regularly, you’ll lower your chances of having drops in energy, or heartburn, indigestion, and other issues with that 22-week pregnant belly. Sounds delicious to us!</belly>
        <checklist>1.Decide: a maternity photographer,2.Decision point: Day care vs. nanny,3.Get your second trimester questions answered,</checklist>
    </week22>

    <week23>
        <description>At 23 weeks pregnant, baby’s getting ready for his or her big debut by listening in on what’s going on in the outside world. We know you’re getting ready too. Just remember: While having the nursery painted and stocked with diapers is important, there are some less fun to-dos you should have on your radar, namely, financials. Week 23 of pregnancy is a good time to call your health insurance company to see how you’re currently covered and decide what adjustments you’ll need to make for baby. Consider writing a will if you don’t have one, or updating your current one. And how’s baby’s savings account going? If you’re like, “What savings account?” now’s a good time to start one. Even making small deposits will help once you factor in time value of money—the earlier you start saving, the faster your money will compound. One study found that kids who have their own savings account are more likely to go to college, and another one estimated the average cost of raising a baby until age 18 to be over $226,000. Whoa!
            How Big Is Baby at 23 Weeks Pregnant?
            You’re 23 weeks pregnant, and baby is as big as a grapefruit! The average 23-week fetus measures 11.4 inches from head to foot and weighs 1.1 pounds. Yep, baby’s almost a foot long, and is finally able to be weighed in pounds! And baby's not just getting bigger, he or she's getting even cuter and starting to look more like a baby.
            23 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            23 weeks pregnant is five months. Can you believe you and your 23-week baby are starting on month six?!</description>
        <symptoms>While you’ve kissed first trimester nausea and fatigue good-bye, you’re dealing with the discomfort that 23 weeks pregnant symptoms can bring. This can include:

            Swollen ankles and feet. Some puffiness is totally normal. Deal with it by putting your feet up as much as you can, taking regular walks, and drinking lots of water. Call your doctor if you get extreme or sudden swelling, which can be a sign of a dangerous pregnancy complication called preeclampsia.
            Braxton Hicks contractions. It’s a totally weird sensation the first time you notice your belly getting super tight! Your muscles are flexing, basically to prep for the Wonder Woman-like tightening they’re going to have to do during labor. So as long as they go away quickly, they’re just par for the pregnancy course. Drink plenty of water and change positions frequently to stay comfortable.
            Backaches. Sorry, but lingering backaches are to be expected, as your growing baby starts to bend your spine and stress your back muscles. Backaches are especially common for women who are 23 weeks pregnant with twins. Pain, on the other hand, could be cause for concern, so tell your OB if it really hurts.
            Bleeding and/or swollen gums. You probably didn’t expect pregnancy to affect your mouth! Pregnancy hormones increase your blood flow, making your gums more likely to swell and bleed. If your mouth is feeling more sensitive than usual, switch to a soft bristle toothbrush and continue flossing with TLC. And stick with your normal dental exam routine, seeing the dentist at least every six months. In fact, your dentist may want to do extra checks while you’re pregnant—but will avoid X-rays, which aren’t usually recommended for pregnant women.</symptoms>
        <belly>A typical 23 weeks pregnant belly measures about 21 to 25 centimeters from the pubic bone to the top of the uterus. (That’s the fundal height.) At 23 weeks pregnant, you’ve probably gained about 12 to 15 pounds. And if you’re 23 weeks pregnant with twins, you should have gained at least 23 pounds so far. By gaining the recommended amount of weight for a twin pregnancy, you’ll reduce your risk of preterm labor.
            At 23 weeks pregnant, baby movement probably feels pretty cool—and it’s always a comfort knowing baby’s in there wiggling around. If you pay attention, you’ll get to know your 23-week fetus’s routine: baby’s less active when he or she is sleeping and a kung fu master when he or she’s awake. Some parents even swear their newborns kept similar routines after birth as they did in utero. So, if your kicker is keeping you up at night, consider this a warning!</belly>
        <checklist>1.Is your life insurance in order?,2.It's time to get baby's nursery ready!,3.Write or update your will,</checklist>
    </week23>

    <week24>
        <description>Consider this a preview of motherhood: Your baby’s doing just fine—and you’re, well, kind of a mess. Your week 24 baby is working on being ready to survive (and thrive!) in the outside world. You, on the other hand, are probably experiencing some of the late-pregnancy discomforts at 24 weeks pregnant—leg cramps, backaches, and swollen feet. Hang in there, mama-to-be!
            How Big Is Baby at 24 Weeks?
            At 24 weeks, baby is the size of a cantaloupe. Your 11.8-inch fetus now weighs about 1.3 pounds.
            24 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            Now that you’re 24 weeks pregnant, you’re five months and about one week pregnant. (If you do simple multiplication, it seems like 24 weeks would be six months pregnant, but remember: all months except February are longer than just four weeks, and those extra days add up!)</description>
        <symptoms>Your (pretty annoying) 24 week pregnant symptoms probably sound a little bit like this:
            Swollen ankles and feet. If your tootsies are puffy, elevate them while you're sitting. Getting up and walking often can help too. A little bit of swelling is totally to be expected but swelling in your face, severe swelling in your hands, or uneven (in one leg and not the other) or sudden swelling aren’t run-of-the-mill. In fact, those are signs of preeclampsia, a dangerous pregnancy complication, so tell your OB if you are experiencing any swelling that seems out of the ordinary.
            Leg cramps. Tight, achy, or “jumpy” legs can be a sign of dehydration. So check that you’re drinking plenty of water. Stretch your legs often, and take lots of walks. Let your doctor know you’re getting leg cramps; they’re probably not an issue, but occasionally cramps can be a sign of another problem, such as a nutritional deficiency, so it’s worth keeping an eye on.
            Backaches. Yep, you’re still experiencing back pain—and it might even be getting worse. That’s because, as baby gets larger, so does your uterus (of course), and your uterus presses against your spine, making it more curved and strained. Plus, your back muscles have to work harder to carry the extra weight. Tell your doctor about any severe pain (a.k.a. sciatica).
            Linea nigra. That's the dark line that runs up the center of your belly. Influenced by pregnancy hormones, the linea nigra should fade within a few weeks to months after giving birth.
            Stretch marks. These “tiger stripes” may continue to appear as your skin stretches even more. If you’re 24 weeks pregnant with twins, you’re probably more likely to get them.</symptoms>
        <belly>At 24 weeks pregnant, you’ve probably been feeling baby kicking for at least a few weeks, but now they’re getting stronger and stronger. In fact, your partner or others who touch your belly might start to feel those kicks soon too.
            Recommended 24 weeks pregnant weight gain is about 14 to 16 pounds for moms-to-be of normal weight. If you’ve gained a bit more than that, don’t worry—it’s drastic or sudden weight gain that’s cause for concern—but for the healthiest pregnancy possible, you’ll want to find ways to keep your weight gain under control.
            Did you know 24 is a magic number for twin moms? It’s recommended that women who are 24 weeks pregnant with twins have gained 24 pounds by now. In fact, if you have, you’ve actually reduced your risk of preterm labor.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Take your glucose challenge test,2.Schedule your 28-week prenatal visit,3.Baby shower gifts – register now,4.Start babyproofing your home</checklist>
    </week24>

    <week25>
        <description>You’re 25 weeks pregnant and it’s probably dawned on you that soon you’ll actually have to deliver this baby. That might be little scary, but it’s also exciting! What’s cool is that most hospitals will let you pre-register for delivery, which means you can fill out your admissions paperwork early so you don’t have to stand around filling out a bunch of forms while in the throes of labor.
            How Big Is Baby at 25 Weeks?
            Baby at 25 weeks is as big as a head of cauliflower, measuring 13.6 inches in length and weighing nearly 1.5 pounds.
            25 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            25 weeks pregnant is five months and about two weeks pregnant.</description>
        <symptoms>While you’re still feeling pretty energetic, you’re probably also starting to feel weighed down by your bigger-by-the-day baby. Your 25 weeks pregnant symptoms may include:
            Trouble sleeping. Maybe you can’t sleep because you’re getting nervous about delivery, or maybe it’s your haywire hormones—or just your big belly getting in the way. Experiment with different strategies for getting some sleep. One idea is to drink extra water early in the day, so you can start tapering off your intake as you get closer to bedtime. That way, you might need fewer bathroom breaks during the night.
            Frequent urination. Now that baby’s crowding your bladder, you’ve got to pee. A lot.
            Constipation. Exercising (it’s as simple as taking regular walks), drinking lots of water, and eating plenty of fiber-rich foods can help you stay, well… regular.
            Hemorrhoids. We can’t sympathize enough about these swollen varicose anal veins. Hemorrhoids are common in the second half of pregnancy because baby is putting a ton of pressure on your digestive tract. And the constipation certainly isn't helping. Getting the constipation under control will help prevent straining while you go to the bathroom and hopefully will prevent future swelling and discomfort.
            Gas and bloating. Your hormones are slowing down digestion, creating excess gas.
            Heartburn. Add this to your list of tummy troubles. Baby is pushing on your digestive tract, which can, in turn, push stomach acid up your esophagus and cause painful burning. Most antacids should be safe during pregnancy (but always check with your doctor!) and also contain lots of calcium as an added bonus. Avoiding greasy and spicy foods can also help with heartburn, especially before bedtime.
            Braxton Hicks contractions. Usually these little “practice contractions” show up around 28 weeks, but some moms-to-be notice them earlier than that. If you get them, you’ll notice your uterus get super hard and tight and then go back to normal. Luckily, Braxton Hicks contractions aren’t frequent and they don’t happen regularly. They’ll also go away if you switch positions. Real contractions, on the other hand, will happen repeatedly and will continue to get stronger and more frequent. If you’re worried your contractions are the real deal and not just practice, call the doctor right away. You could be going into preterm labor—some moms-to-be are more at risk for going into labor early, including those who are 25 weeks pregnant with twins—and sometimes preterm labor can be stopped if it’s caught early enough.</symptoms>
        <belly>You’ve probably gained about 15 to 18 pounds total so far. Are you 25 weeks pregnant with twins? For you it’s probably more like 25 to 40 pounds.
            When you’re 25 weeks pregnant, weight gain can be a source of anxiety. We know, we know, we’ve been telling you to gain slowly and steadily, but it’s also really common for the number on your scale to jump around during this time in the second trimester. Part of that may be due to the amount of water weight pregnant women put on in mid-pregnancy. And realistically, gaining the exact same amount of weight each week just isn’t going to happen—there are naturally going to be some fluctuations—your doctor just wants you to make healthy weight gain a goal so you and baby stay as healthy as possible. (And also so your third trimester isn’t miserable because you’re carrying around a lot of extra weight!)
            So don’t sweat a few extra pounds, and keep up with your healthy eating and exercise. If your weight gain really is a problem, your doctor will let you know. Instead of stressing too much about your weight, focus on what’s going on inside that 25 weeks pregnant belly.
            Fetal movement at 25 weeks has become more noticeable—and you’re probably noticing some patterns. When you’re feeling lots of kicks, baby’s awake, and when you’re not, he or she is likely snoozing. Regular movement is a sign of a healthy, active baby. If you haven’t felt baby move in a while and you want some reassurance that everything’s okay, drink some ice water, play some music, or have your partner give you a light massage, and your little one might just wake up and give you a few jabs.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Rent on-trend maternity clothes,2.Jet off for a final trip!,3.Help your baby shower host,</checklist>
    </week25>

    <week26>
        <description>You haven’t met baby yet, but he or she’s taking over your life! Interfering with your sleep. Messing with your memory. And even giving you a stress headache or two at 26 weeks pregnant. Um, he or she will do all those things after birth too! When they say we have nine months to get ready for baby, they don’t just mean growing the baby and buying a car seat and bouncer. We need to mentally prepare for a newborn to become the center of our attention. And already, at week 26 of pregnancy, baby’s giving you some practice in that department.
            How Big Is Baby at 26 Weeks Pregnant?
            At 26 weeks pregnant, baby is as big as a head of kale. Your 26-week fetus measures about 14 weeks and weighs about 1.7 pounds. He or she is developing senses, features, and even talents! Wow!
            26 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            26 weeks pregnant is five months and about three weeks pregnant. You’re making your way through the sixth month of pregnancy.</description>
        <symptoms>Your 26 weeks pregnant symptoms are mostly discomforts—and are steadily getting more uncomfortable as baby grows and your body begins to make changes to get ready for childbirth.
            Trouble sleeping. Yawn! The closer you get to your due date, the tougher it might be to get some rest! Watch your caffeine intake, stay hydrated, and get a little exercise (take walks!) to help your body settle down at night.
            Swelling. You might not like the puffiness, but it’s normal to have some mild swelling around week 26 of pregnancy. But it’s important to watch out for swelling that’s severe or sudden, which could be a sign of a dangerous condition called preeclampsia. Call your doctor if your swelling seems worrisome.
            Headaches. These are often due to hormone fluctuations or stress. But you can get also get headaches if you’re hungry or dehydrated, so continue taking care of yourself and baby by eating at least every few hours and keeping a glass of water by your side for frequent sipping.
            Pregnancy brain. Is it getting tricky to remember stuff? That may be a physiological symptom of hormone fluctuations, but it also might be because, well, you’ve got quite a bit on your mind.
            Braxton Hicks contractions. Notice your belly occasionally feeling really tight? That’s a contraction. Yep, already. (Braxton Hicks might be more noticeable for women who are 26 weeks pregnant with twins.) Don’t freak out though—your muscles are flexing to practice for labor. As long as the contractions aren’t steady or severe, they’re run-of-the-mill. Tell your doctor if the contractions are painful or don’t stop; those are signs of preterm labor.
            Higher blood pressure. A slight boost in blood pressure is normal at 26 weeks pregnant. If your doctor sees too high of a boost though, she might have you monitored more closely. That’s because hypertension—a systolic reading of more than 140 mm Hg or diastolic reading more than 90 mm Hg—could be a sign of preeclampsia or HELLP syndrome. These potentially dangerous pregnancy complications would need to be treated right away.</symptoms>
        <belly>By 26 weeks pregnant, you’ve probably gained about 16 to 22 pounds—or about 27 to 42 pounds if you’re 26 weeks pregnant with twins. When you touch your 26 weeks pregnant belly, you’ll notice the top of your uterus is about 2.5 inches above your belly button. Your belly will keep growing about a half inch each week for the rest of your pregnancy.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Tour your maternity ward,2.Preregister with the hospital,3.Communicate with your baby,4.Spend time with your partner,</checklist>
    </week26>

    <week27>
        <description>Raise your sparkling water glass and say goodbye to the second trimester! At 27 weeks, baby is breathing (it’s amniotic fluid, not air, but still pretty cool) and even showing brain activity. You’ve got a lot on your brain, too, from wondering what the birth is going to be like to trying to find the best pediatrician for baby. As you look ahead to the third trimester, be prepared for some pretty embarrassing stuff (like having to pee all the time—and maybe even when you don’t mean to!). It’s all par for the late-pregnancy course and totally temporary. It’s time to head down the home stretch. Are you ready?
            How Big Is Baby at 27 Weeks?
            At 27 weeks pregnant, baby is as big as a head of lettuce. The average 27-week fetus measures 14.4 inches and weighs 1.9 pounds. But baby's not just getting bigger—he or she is also getting smarter.
            27 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            27 weeks pregnant is five months and four weeks pregnant. This is the last week of the sixth month and the last week of the second trimester.</description>
        <symptoms>The annoying symptoms you’ve been having aren’t likely to go away anytime soon, but at least you’ve probably found some ways to deal with them—and hey, maybe you’re even used to them right now. The most common 27 weeks pregnant symptoms are:
            Leg cramps. Keep stretching those legs—flexing your feet can help—and drinking lots of water to prevent these ouchies.
            Backaches. Gentle stretching can help your back, too. Consider sleeping with one of those huge body pillows, which can ease some of the pressure on your hips and help you get into a comfy position for your back.
            Constipation. If you’re stopped up and you’ve done all the usual prevention—eaten lots of fibrous foods, drank lots of water, and taken plenty of walks—ask your doctor if a fiber supplement or stool softener is safe to take.
            Hemorrhoids. Straining to go to the bathroom and all the pressure baby’s putting on your lower half can cause this not-so-pretty 27 weeks pregnancy symptom.
            Skin, hair, and nail changes. Notch this one into the unpredictable pregnancy symptom category. Your skin, hair, and nails might be thicker or grow faster (yay!) but they might also be more brittle (boo).
            Snissing. This is what we call peeing when you sneeze. Baby is putting a ton of pressure on your bladder and there’s not much you can do about it except take frequent pit stops to empty your bladder and maybe wear a pantiliner if you’re worried about an unexpected achoo.
            Women who are 27 weeks pregnant with twins are vulnerable to preterm labor, so if you notice any pregnancy symptoms that are out of the ordinary—such as bleeding, watery discharge, abdominal pains, or consistent, repeated contractions, tell your OB right away.</symptoms>
        <belly>Healthy weight gain at 27 weeks pregnant is around 15 to 30 pounds. If you’ve gained more quickly than recommended—two or more pounds per week—your OB may tell you to slow it down a bit. Sounds rough, but she can give you some tips on keeping the weight gain under control. By sticking to pregnancy weight gain recommendations, you’re reducing your risk of pregnancy complications and preterm labor. You’re also making your third trimester a little easier by not having extra pounds to carry around town with you.
            If you’re 27 weeks pregnant with twins, you’ve probably gained more weight—about 29 to 44 pounds. Still, your twins are growing and developing at about the same rate as singleton babies do—though one baby is probably a bit smaller than the other.
            You’re probably feeling a ton of kicks inside that 27 weeks pregnant belly—twice as many if you’re 27 weeks pregnant with twins. You may even feel tiny hiccups, which are like patterns of little twitches. For now, sit back and enjoy the kicks and jabs. Next week, you should start counting kicks to make sure baby seems consistently active from day to day.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Pick a pediatrician,2.Decision point: Who will be in the delivery room?,3.Make a birth plan,4.Practice labor exercises,</checklist>
    </week27>

    <week28>
        <description>Welcome to the third trimester! Moms-to-be who are 28 weeks pregnant and beyond are known for their lack of sleep. If you find yourself up in the middle of the night, do something relaxing. This is not the time to vacuum the house from top to bottom—even though you might feel the urge to do that at some point. (It’s called nesting. You’ve probably heard of it.) Instead, read a book, drink chamomile tea, or listen to soothing music. Then get back to bed and try to get some rest!
            How Big Is Baby at 28 Weeks Pregnant?
            At 28 weeks, baby is the size of an eggplant. Putting on layers of fat, your baby now measures about 14.8 inches from head to toe and weighs in around 2.2 pounds.
            28 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            When you hit the 28-week mark, you are six months pregnant. This week, you’re embarking on both your seventh month and your third trimester. Can you believe you’ve made it this far?!</description>
        <symptoms>As your body gets more and more crowded by your growing 28-week fetus and starts prepping for his or her arrival, you might be noticing some new pregnancy symptoms. These are common at this stage of the game:
            Trouble sleeping. As you get closer to your due date, you'll likely have more and more trouble getting Zzzs (which stinks, because you’re beat!). It could be hormones or nerves—or both!—causing your inability to snooze.
            Shortness of breath. Baby continues to crowd your lungs and diaphragm, making it tougher to catch your breath. Give yourself permission not to push too hard and to take breaks.
            Aches and pains. The third trimester can be really uncomfortable due to hormone fluctuations and the toll pregnancy is taking on your body. (We’re especially talking to you mamas who are 28 weeks pregnant with twins!) To deal, do yoga, stretch, swim, walk, and/or get a prenatal massage. Try wearing a maternity support belt if you’re on your feet a lot. Not sexy, we know, but it can relieve some of the pressure that’s making you so achy.
            Braxton Hicks contractions. These practice contractions might be getting stronger, more noticeable, or more frequent as your body gets ready for labor. Keep an eye out and be sure that the contractions are only occasional. If they’re regular and continue getting closer together, and don’t stop when you switch positions, you could be in preterm labor and should call the OB ASAP!
            Leaky boobs. Your breasts may already be producing baby's first food, a yellowish substance called colostrum. And surprise! Some of it might actually come out before baby does!</symptoms>
        <belly>Your OB will probably measure your 28 weeks pregnant belly at your prenatal appointment. This week, fundal height—the distance from your pubic bone to the top of your uterus—should be about 26 to 30 centimeters. Knowing you’re measuring within that normal range is reassurance that baby’s growth is on track and that baby’s in the right position, since a breech or sideways position could affect the measurement. For women who are 28 weeks pregnant with twins on the other hand, fundal height usually isn’t measured. That’s because it’s harder for doctors to estimate an “average” for twin pregnancies.
            Doctors recommend you start doing kick counts at 28 weeks. You’ll be keeping tabs on how often baby’s moving and whether his or her movements are consistent from day to day. Here’s how you do it: Pick a time of day and set a timer. See how long it takes to get to 10 fetal movements—it should be less than two hours. The next day at the same approximate time, do the same thing. Record the times each day, and you’ll start to find an average range for your baby. It’s great reassurance that he or she’s doing well in there. If anything seems inconsistent, let your doctor know.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Schedule your 30-week prenatal visit,2.Count fetal kicks,3.Find out pain relief options for your big labor day,</checklist>
    </week28>

    <week29>
        <description>Hey you! You’re probably getting a preview of baby’s personality by feeling him or her move. By those playful kicks and jabs, you may realize you’ve got a gentle dancer… or an active ninja! Week 29 of pregnancy is a good time to start finalizing details, like stocking the nursery with baby care essentials and checking out a few potential day cares. You’ll also want to start packing a bag with the things you know you’ll want with you at the hospital for baby’s birth. Leave it by the door, so you can add items you think of along the way—and so you can grab it at a moment’s notice.
            How Big Is Baby at 29 Weeks?
            At 29 weeks, baby is the size of an acorn squash. Your 29 weeks baby already measures about 15.2 inches long. And he or she weighs about 2.5 pounds, but still has a way to go—can you believe baby will triple in weight before birth?
            29 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            29 weeks pregnant is six months and one week pregnant.</description>
        <symptoms>At 29 weeks pregnant, baby's not just moving a lot, but also plumping up. And as baby continues to put pressure on your digestive system, you’re going to feel the effects: hemorrhoids, heartburn, pelvic pain, and frequent urination are all common at this stage in the game.
            Headaches and/or lightheadedness. You can get a headache or feel out of sorts if you’re sleep deprived. (We know it’s probably been tough to get a restful night of sleep!) But it could be from low blood sugar too, so make sure you're eating at regular intervals.
            Itchy belly. Your skin is stretching thinner, making it more sensitive. Lotion up and drink lots of water! Let your doctor know about any intense itches or a rash.
            Back, leg, or hip pain. Some soreness is totally par for the course. Your body’s carrying around extra weight all day at 29 weeks pregnant, and depending on baby’s position, he or she is putting pressure on anything and everything. (Even more so if you’re 29 weeks pregnant with twins!) Plus, your joints and ligaments are getting softer and more relaxed in preparation for delivery. All of that pressure can cause aches and pains all over.
            Hemorrhoids. Baby's putting pressure on your digestive system too, and those pesky hormones may be relaxing your intestinal muscles, causing uncomfortable hemorrhoids. Combat them by eating plenty of fiber—think leafy veggies—and drinking lots of water.
            Constipation. This isn't really helping the hemorrhoid situation, is it? The fiber and water will help here as well.
            Trouble sleeping. Don’t overdo it with caffeine, drink lots of water, and get some light exercise. We’re big fans of prenatal yoga and brisk walks around the neighborhood (or the mall!).
            Frequent urination. Gotta pee… again?! The more your uterus expands, the more you'll probably have to hit the restroom. This doesn’t mean cut down on drinking water. ICYMI, proper hydration is important for easing many 29 weeks pregnancy symptoms; it’s also important for preventing preterm labor. (You’re at higher risk for preterm labor if you have a pregnancy complication or if you’re 29 weeks pregnant with twins.)</symptoms>
        <belly>29 weeks pregnant weight gain is typically about 19 to 25 pounds. For women who are 29 weeks pregnant with twins, weight gain is around 23 to 38 pounds. If you feel around your 29-week pregnant belly with your hand, you’ll notice the top of your uterus is about 3.5 to 4 inches above your belly button.
            You’ll also notice lots of kicks inside your 29 weeks pregnant belly. Baby is starting to feel a bit crowded, and thanks to surging energy levels, is pretty active. Continue doing kick counts each day to make sure baby’s activity levels seem pretty consistent. Baby should move 10 times in two hours or less.
            If you haven’t felt baby move in a little while and you’re starting to worry, drink some ice water, play some music, or lie down on your side for a nice massage (ask your partner!). One of those activities should wake baby up. Anytime you’re worried about fetal activity, call your doctor; she may want to have baby checked out.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Read up on third trimester tests,2.Hire your caregiver or select a day care, if you need one post-baby,3.Stock up on baby essentials,</checklist>
    </week29>

    <week30>
        <description>Starting to feel like a walking belly? Your 30 weeks pregnant belly is doing more than just making it tough to find a comfortable sleeping position. It’s made itself a conversation piece. Everywhere you go, someone seems to have a comment about how you look, which isn’t always so fun. And no doubt, you’ve encountered one or two people who don’t think before they speak and say something embarrassing or hurtful (what’s up with that?). Try not to take those comments seriously, but know which ones should be taken to heart. Like when someone tells you you’re glowing, believe them. You are! And take advantage of some of the perks. When someone offers you their seat on a crowded train—take it!
            How Big Is Baby at 30 Weeks?
            At 30 weeks pregnant, baby is the size of a zucchini. Your 15.7-inch, 2.9-pound, 30-week fetus continues to grow about half a pound and half an inch each week.
            30 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            30 weeks pregnant is six months and two weeks pregnant. Just 10 weeks (give or take, of course!) to go.</description>
        <symptoms>At week 30 of pregnancy, your dreams might be getting even weirder— if you’re actually sleeping, that is. That could be the result of hormones, but it could also be anxiety, so consider doing some prep work to help you rest easier. One idea? Do a test drive to see exactly how long it takes you to get to the hospital. Then maybe you’ll stop having nightmares about giving birth in your car. Here are other common 30 weeks pregnant symptoms:
            Heartburn. If you’re feeling the burn, pay attention to which foods may be causing it. (Often, that’s greasy, heavy, spicy, or acidic food.) Avoid them as much as you can, especially before bedtime, since this annoying 30 weeks pregnant symptom can make sleep hard to come by.
            Trouble sleeping. You’re tossing and turning because you can’t get comfortable—and because your mind is racing. It’s such a vicious cycle that leads to another issue: fatigue.
            Swelling. A little puffiness is to be expected, and will typically go down if you put your feet up for a while. Just know that sudden or severe swelling can be a sign of a problem, so keep an eye out for that.
            General discomfort. Thanks to your big belly, your back aches, your hips ache, and your feet… well, they ache too!
            Shortness of breath. Those lungs just keep getting more crowded, right? Baby is still up high near your rib cage during pregnancy at 30 weeks, but should drop down into your pelvis a little later in your pregnancy—maybe as soon as week 33 or 34. You’ll know when he or she does because you’ll be able to take a deep breath again. Ah!</symptoms>
        <belly>Whoa! You might notice your 30 weeks pregnant belly getting pretty hard and tight at times. Yep, at 30 weeks pregnant Braxton Hicks contractions are pretty common. These are your body’s way of gearing up for the main event (labor, of course). Braxton Hicks tend to happen after exercise or sex, or when you’re tired or dehydrated. If you get them, sit down or lie on your side, relax, and drink water. If the contractions don’t stop, or if you have four or more in an hour, call your doctor. It could actually be preterm labor.
            Total 30 weeks pregnant weight gain should be about 18 to 25 pounds. However, if you’re pregnant with twins, it may be more like 25 to 40 pounds. Fundal height—the distance from your pubic bone to the top of your uterus—should be around 28 to 32 centimeters.
            Worried about the weight gain? Don’t be. The extra pounds you’ve put on will act as reserves to help you breastfeed baby. There’s no need to agonize over them or to rush to take them off; it’s taken you nine months to put the weight on, and it will take at least that long to take it off. Do keep your eye on the scale, however, because sudden or drastic weight gain could be the sign of a serious pregnancy complication called preeclampsia, so you should notify your doctor right away if the number on your scale jumps higher than it usually does week-to-week.
            During pregnancy at 30 weeks, baby’s position is still head up. Your 30-week fetus is floating comfortably in about 1½ pints of amniotic fluid. It may seem cramped in there, but he or she still has room to move around. Over the upcoming weeks, your belly will grow even further past your rib cage to accommodate baby, but he or she will still get a little more crowded as you approach your due date.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Schedule your 32-week prenatal visit,2.Get help for baby's home arrival,3.Practice a hospital run,</checklist>
    </week30>

    <week31>
        <description>Can you believe all five of baby’s senses are fully developed at 31 weeks pregnant? Baby's also getting smarter! In the meantime, you might actually feel a little… dumb. You’re not! It’s just that many moms-to-be find themselves acting absentmindedly during the third trimester. Some say that “pregnancy brain” isn’t a real thing, but can you honestly think of another time in your life when you’ve had as much on your mind as now? We’re guessing no. That right there is enough of a reason to be so forgetful at week 31 of pregnancy.
            How Big Is Baby at 31 Weeks?
            At 31 weeks pregnant, baby is as big as a bunch of asparagus. Baby's about 16.2 inches long and weighs about 3.3 pounds. Baby's getting so big, he or she's probably crowding your lungs, which is why you might find yourself winded on a normal walk up the stairs.
            31 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            31 weeks pregnant is six months and three weeks pregnant. You’re wrapping up month seven at the end of this week.</description>
        <symptoms>From week 31 of pregnancy on, you’re bound to feel a lot of the same symptoms you’ve already been experiencing. Some may get worse, and some may become bearable. Here are the most typical 31 weeks pregnant symptoms:
            Shortness of breath. You might start to have more trouble getting around as you get heavier and more short of breath. Remember not to push yourself too much. It’s good for you and baby to get some exercise, but definitely take breaks to rest as much as you need to.
            Dry, brittle nails. Sure, you’re having extra finger- and toenail growth, but that can make those nails feel dry and easily broken. Some moms-to-be have success with a moisturizing cuticle oil. This may also be the perfect excuse for a spa mani-pedi.
            Braxton Hicks contractions. To ease the discomfort of Braxton Hicks, drink plenty of water and change positions often. This will prevent those “practice contractions” from turning into preterm labor. If you have certain pregnancy complications, or if you’re 31 weeks pregnant with twins, you’re at higher risk for preterm labor.
            Leaky boobs. That yellow liquid is baby's first food, called colostrum, and your body’s getting it ready for the big arrival.
            Frequent urination. Your bladder's just as crowded as your lungs are. Not much you can do about it except mentally plan more bathroom breaks into your daily routine.
            Backaches. Be sure to keep stretching to ease your aching back. That prenatal yoga class can help!
            Trouble sleeping. It’s no wonder you can’t sleep when your back hurts, your belly’s contracting, you can’t find a comfortable position, oh—and you have to keep getting up to pee!</symptoms>
        <belly>By 31 weeks pregnant you’ve probably gained about 21 to 27 pounds. If you’re 31 weeks pregnant with twins, it’s more like 27 to 42 pounds.
            Your 31 weeks pregnant belly is getting in the way of everyday things like tying your shoes and sex. It’s even in the way of your usual swagger—have you started waddling yet?!</belly>
        <checklist>1.Prep your pets for baby,2.Learn the signs of preterm labor,3.Babyproof your nursery,4.Order a baby keepsake book,</checklist>
    </week31>

    <week32>
        <description>Ready or not?! At 32 weeks pregnant, baby’s birth still seems far into the future, but you and baby are getting ready in a lot of ways… just in case there’s an early arrival. You’re probably dealing with some end-of-pregnancy to-dos, like telling your health insurance there’ll be a new arrival soon, and figuring out how the heck to install an infant car seat. Your 32-week fetus has probably turned into the head-down position (or will turn soon), so he or she poised for the trip down the birth canal. Don’t worry: You still have a little more time to mentally prepare for that!
            How Big Is Baby at 32 Weeks?
            Your 32-week baby is as big as a squash. Still growing strong, baby measures about 16.7 inches and weighs in at about 3.8 pounds at 32 weeks pregnant.
            32 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            32 weeks pregnant in months is seven months pregnant. Welcome to month 8!</description>
        <symptoms>Intensity is building in the symptoms department, since heartburn and contractions tend to get more noticeable around week 32 of pregnancy. But we’re guessing you’re so excited about baby’s impending arrival, these 32 weeks pregnant symptoms aren’t slowing you down—at least not too much.
            More Braxton Hicks contractions. Those “practice contractions” are likely getting more frequent and stronger. (This might be confused with 32 weeks pregnant cramping.) There’s one big difference between Braxton Hicks contractions and the real deal: These guys go away. Real contractions just keep coming. Women who are 32 weeks pregnant with twins are at higher risk for preterm labor, so definitely watch for contractions that don’t let up.
            Darker nipples. Whoa! Suddenly those areolas look darker. No one knows exactly why, but one theory is they darken so that baby can see them better for breastfeeding. Your body’s pretty amazing, huh?
            Shortness of breath. Don't worry: baby is getting plenty of air. You’re not though, so don’t push yourself too hard.
            Heartburn. Go ahead and pop an antacid. They’re safe for most moms-to-be to take during pregnancy.
            Leaky boobs. Your breasts are probably noticeably bigger and they may even have begun producing colostrum, which is the thick yellow fluid that baby will eat in the first few days of life. Don’t be surprised to see a little bit leaking at this point. Yikes!
            Vaginal discharge. Might seem a little gross, but the increased discharge is your body’s way of preparing for delivery; it prevents infection down there. Keep your eye out for the mucus plug—this thick, gooey (sometimes bloody) substance covers the cervix until a few days (or just hours) before labor, when your body expels it. Another thing to keep an eye on: discharge that seems more like a watery liquid. If you’re having a constant flow that’s more like water than discharge, your water might have broken, causing a slow leak. If that’s the case, call the OB and get to the hospital stat.</symptoms>
        <belly>A 32 weeks pregnant belly should measure about 30 to 34 centimeters from the top of the uterus to the pelvic bone. Sometime between now and around week 34, baby will “drop” from up near your ribs to down near your pelvis, where he or she will hang out in the head-down position until delivery. When this happens you may notice you suddenly go from “carrying high” to “carrying low.” This isn’t a guarantee though; some babies don’t drop until mom’s actually in labor.
            If you’re 32 weeks pregnant with twins, you’re obviously feeling more weighed down than other 32-weeks pregnant women. And chances are, you’re also even closer to delivery, since the average twin pregnancy is considered full-term at 37 weeks.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Schedule your 34-week prenatal visit,2.Call your health insurance company,3.Install baby's car seat,</checklist>
    </week32>

    <week33>
        <description>We’d tell you to take a deep breath and relax, but it’s probably tough to do either of those at 33 weeks pregnant. It’s probably tough to be comfortable at all, since you might be feeling overheated on top of your other symptoms, too. But you’re probably getting super excited to meet baby, and we can’t blame you. Week 33 of pregnancy is a good time to start packing your hospital bag. You might also want to read up on postpartum care and stock your medicine cabinet with some essential new mom care supplies. (The hospital will have plenty as well, so no need to worry if you overlook something.) Sure, you might not see baby for another month, but if you have an early surprise arrival, at least you won’t have to think about which shirt to pack or whether or not you have hemorrhoid cream at home. (About that… sorry.)
            How Big Is Baby at 33 Weeks?
            At 33 weeks pregnant, baby is as big as a head of celery. He or she weighs about 4.2 pounds and measures about 17.2 inches—and may grow up to a full inch this week. Amazing!
            33 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            33 weeks pregnant is 7 months and about one week pregnant.</description>
        <symptoms>33 weeks pregnant symptoms in one word? Discomfort! Here’s what you’re probably feeling this week.
            Overheating. You’re one hot mama-to-be because your metabolic rate is through the roof.
            Headaches. Hormone fluctuations at 33 weeks can cause headaches. So can stress or dehydration, so try to take it easy and drink plenty of water. A few extra trips to the ladies’ room is worth the sacrifice.
            Shortness of breath. By now, you may be used to not being able to fully catch your breath (especially if you’re 33 weeks pregnant with twins). Imagine what a relief it will be when baby “drops” and frees up some space around your lungs. For different moms-to-be, this happens at different times, but chances are, it could be very soon.
            Forgetfulness and clumsiness. This is the unproven phenomenon also known as “baby brain.” Your flightiness may be less due to your physiological changes and more due to the stress and anxiety of expecting a baby in less than two months.</symptoms>
        <belly>By 33 weeks pregnant, you may have gained around 22 to 28 pounds total—32 to 42 pounds if you’re 33 weeks pregnant with twins. For some moms-to-be, having some extra curves makes them feel sexy. Know that as long as your doctor has said sex is okay during your pregnancy, you can continue to enjoy it right up until delivery day.
            If you feel your belly tightening occasionally, you’re probably having Braxton Hicks contractions. Here’s how you know: Braxton Hicks aren’t painful and often happen after sex or exercise.
            They’re different from regular contractions because they stop when you switch positions. Real contractions keep going—there’d be at least five in an hour—and mean actual labor. Yep! And it’s early still, so at this point having real contractions would be considered preterm labor.
            Certain complications and conditions make you more likely to go into labor early, such as having excess amniotic fluid, being dehydrated, or being 33 weeks pregnant with twins.
            At 33 weeks pregnant, cramping like you’d have with a period could be a sign of preterm labor. So can vaginal bleeding, unusual discharge, or leaking. At 33 weeks pregnant, pressure in your pelvis could be a sign too. Be on the lookout for these symptoms. If anything worries you, empty your bladder, lie on your left side, drink water, and call your OB immediately.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Pack your hospital bag,2.Prep for postpartum care,3.Inquire about hospital resources,</checklist>
    </week33>

    <week34>
        <description>Watch what you say! Your curious baby can hear your voice and is listening in on your conversations at 34 weeks pregnant. In fact, baby might enjoy a lullaby or two—so go ahead and sing to him or her. Some experts say that, after birth, babies can recognize songs mom sang while pregnant; they may even be more easily soothed by those familiar tunes once they're “on the outside.” And no, baby won’t care if you’re singing a bit off-key.
            How Big Is Baby at 34 Weeks?
            At 34 weeks pregnant, baby is the size of a butternut squash. With less than two months until go time, baby weighs in at about 4.7 pounds and measures about 17.7 inches.
            34 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            34 weeks pregnant is seven months and about two weeks pregnant. You’re only about six weeks away from becoming a mom.</description>
        <symptoms>Your symptoms at week 34 of pregnancy are pretty typical to late pregnancy and might seem like a broken record from here on out.
            Blurry vision. A combination of hormones, fluid buildup, and lack of sleep may make your vision seem a little “off.” Sometimes it’s just a normal, temporary pregnancy symptom, but if your blurry vision is accompanied by swelling, headache, rapid weight gain and/or swelling, it could be a sign of preeclampsia, so tell your OB right away.
            Fatigue. It’s exhausting carrying around all that extra weight (whether you’ve got one baby in there or you’re 34 weeks pregnant with twins!). And if only you could sleep at night!
            Constipation. It’s normal to be stopped up at 34 weeks pregnant, which can make you feel more uncomfortable than you already are. Remember to take frequent walks, eat foods with lots of fiber (think leafy greens), and drink lots of water to get things moving.
            Hemorrhoids. What a vicious cycle! Straining when you go to the bathroom can cause this other not-at-all-fun symptom. So can all the extra weight baby’s putting on your rectum. To ease hemorrhoids, work on the constipation and try different sitting and standing positions to ease some of the pressure on the area.
            Swollen ankles and feet. Sit down and put up your feet whenever you can to reduce the swelling.
            Abdominal pressure. As baby prepares for arrival and settles down lower, you might feel pressure in your pelvis and even more frequent urination.
            Braxton Hicks contractions. At 34 weeks pregnant, cramping sensations are totally normal. It’s likely your body just getting ready for the real deal. Note, though, that at 34 weeks pregnant, pelvic pain could be the sign of a problem. Regular contractions that don’t stop after about an hour, vaginal bleeding, and lower back pain are all signs of premature labor. If you have any of these worrisome symptoms at 34 weeks, call your OB immediately.</symptoms>
        <belly>Your 34 weeks pregnant belly might seem a little—or a lot—lower than it did a few weeks ago. That’s because baby may have descended lower into your pelvis. This may let you breathe a little easier, since your lungs have more space. Ahh! (Of course, some babies don’t do this until the day they’re born, so we’re not making any guarantees.) The pitfall of this descent, of course, is even more pressure on your bladder, so be prepared to make even more trips to the ladies’ room over the coming weeks.
            A 34 weeks pregnant, your belly should measure about 32 to 36 inches from the top of the uterus to the pubic bone. If you’re measuring a bit big or a bit small, it could mean baby’s bigger or smaller than average or in a breech or sideways position, or that there is an abnormal level of amniotic fluid. Anything out of the ordinary with fundal height (that belly measurement) may prompt your doctor to order a 34 weeks pregnant ultrasound to figure out the cause.
            Fun fact: Amniotic fluid is at an all-time high between weeks 34 and 36, so you might feel as if your belly isn’t getting too much bigger after this point. That’s because fluid will decrease so baby can keep growing and have room to wiggle around. Still, he or she is getting snug in there, causing movement to start to feel slightly different around this time.
            Continue checking in on baby by doing kick counts. Set a timer and see how much time it takes baby to move ten times. (It should be an hour or less.) Then check back each day to make sure the approximate time is pretty similar. Let your doctor know about any notable changes.
            If you’re 34 weeks pregnant with twins, you might be feeling pretty antsy. That could be a subtle psychological sign that the babies are coming soon. For twin moms-to-be, the countdown is officially on, since the average twin pregnancy lasts about 35 to 37 weeks. If there’s no need to deliver your babies early, you’re likely to go into labor around 37 weeks.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Schedule your 36-week prenatal visit,2.Try a perineal massage,3.Write your baby shower thank-you notes,</checklist>
    </week34>

    <week35>
        <description>Ready as you’ll ever be! At 35 weeks, some moms-to-be feel like they have a ton of stuff left to do before baby’s arrival. Others can barely wait for baby to make his or her debut. Either way, try not to stress; baby will show up when he or she's ready, and won’t care if you haven’t checked every little detail off your list. As long as you’ve got a safe place for baby to sleep and an infant car seat for the ride home, you’ve already got baby’s basic needs taken care of.
            How Big Is Baby at 35 Weeks?
            At 35 weeks pregnant, baby is as big as a pineapple. Baby measures about 18.2 inches from head to heel. From here on out, he or she won't get much longer, but will keep plumping up. Your 35-week fetus now weighs about 5.3 pounds, and will put on a pound or more of baby fat before you meet him or her.
            35 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            35 weeks pregnant is seven month and about three weeks pregnant. This is the last week of your eighth month. Just about five more weeks left!</description>
        <symptoms>As you wrap up your eighth month, you’re probably feeling some of these 35 weeks pregnant symptoms:
            Frequent urge to pee. Yup, your bladder's being pressed on by baby (or babies, if you’re 35 weeks pregnant with twins), who’s likely sitting pretty low in your pelvis, getting ready for birth. Don’t let the extra trips to the bathroom deter you from drinking lots of water though—dehydration puts you at risk for preterm labor, so drink up.
            Constipation. We’ve said it before and we’ll say it again: make sure to get plenty of fiber in your diet. If you’ve tried everything and are still struggling with constipation, ask your doctor if it’s okay for you to take a fiber supplement or a stool softener.
            Aches and pains in the hips and pelvis. These ouchies are continuing—and you may even be feeling a few new ones. While you’re dealing with discomfort, look on the bright side: It’s a sign your body is getting ready to deliver your baby. Yep, all of this pain actually has a purpose! Your ligaments are loosening so that baby can make his or her way out of your uterus and into the world.
            Braxton Hicks Contractions. At 35 weeks pregnant, you may have noticed an increase in the number of contractions you're having. It’s kind of crazy how hard your belly can get! Just keep an eye on those contractions; rest when you get them and drink lots of water.</symptoms>
        <belly>Growing, growing, growing. Yup, baby and you. Now that you’ve reached 35 weeks pregnant, your uterus has grown to about 1,000 times its original size, a number that might sound exaggerated to everyone else—but to you it probably feels more like a million. You can expect to gain about a half-pound each week until you give birth.
            35 weeks pregnant is a good time to review the signs of labor. You may think this is early, but about 11 percent of singleton moms give birth prematurely, while moms who are 35 weeks pregnant with twins are just about considered full term at this point. To recap, here are the signs of actual, real deal, call-the-OB-and-grab-your-hospital-bag labor:
            Water breaking. You’ll know your water has broken if you’re experiencing something that’s less like discharge and more like a flow of water. It can happen in a big gush (like in the movies) or in a slow trickle that just keeps coming.
            Painful contractions. Those Braxton Hicks have nothing on real contractions. If suddenly you’re feeling pain in your 35 weeks pregnant belly or back, instead of some mild tightness, it could be time.
            Regular contractions. True contractions happen regularly and don’t stop—they’ll keep getting more and more frequent and more painful. Your doctor will probably tell you at what point to call her and let her know about your contractions. A good rule of thumb is to call when contractions are about 5 minutes apart for a first pregnancy. If it’s not your first, call earlier—more like when they’re 10 to 15 minutes apart, since second (and later) labors tend to be much shorter.
            Unsure if any 35 weeks pregnant symptom could be a sign of labor? Always call the doc just to be safe.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Get ready to announce baby's arrival,2.Get to know the signs of labor,3.Program important numbers into your phones,</checklist>
    </week35>

    <week36>
        <description>It’s month 9 already? Time is flying! Since baby really could decide to arrive any day now, try to put in your final prep work at 36 weeks pregnant. For example, if you took a childbirth class a few months ago, re-read the materials you were given and practice the breathing techniques you learned with your partner. Go over your plan for getting to the hospital and all the what-ifs. Update your boss and colleagues of the status of all your work projects so they know where to take over if you’re suddenly out of the office. Week 36 of pregnancy is also a good time to enjoy a date with your partner. We’re guessing you won’t be up for dancing, but how about a nice dinner?
            How Big Is Baby at 36 Weeks?
            At 36 weeks pregnant, baby is as big as a papaya, measuring about 18.7 inches from crown to heel and weighing in around 5.8 pounds.
            36 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            36 weeks is eight months pregnant. Welcome to the first week of month 9! You’re just four weeks away from your due date.</description>
        <symptoms>When you have just four weeks to go, pretty much all your symptoms have to do with the fact that baby’s almost here. Your 36 weeks pregnant symptoms may include:
            Better ability to breathe. As baby descends into your pelvis, your lungs will have more space, and you’ll be able to breathe more deeply.
            Pelvic discomfort. You’re feeling this one for the same reason you can breathe again! Baby’s down low, putting pressure on your pelvis. Look out for signs of labor though, including regular, persistent contractions.
            Trouble sleeping. Finding yourself up at 3 a.m. writing thank-you notes or reorganizing the closet? We’ve been there! Find some ways to relax even if you aren't getting much shut-eye.
            Heartburn. Your growing baby is crowding your digestive system, preventing it from working the way it did when you weren’t pregnant. Antacids can help (as long as your doctor has okayed them). Prevent heartburn as much as you can by avoiding citrusy, spicy, vinegary, and greasy foods. (No fun, we know, but it’s worth avoiding the pain.)
            Swollen ankles and feet. Minor swelling is totally normal at 36 weeks pregnant and you’re even more likely to have it if you’re 36 weeks pregnant with twins. You might find that almost as soon as you deliver your baby, it completely disappears. Seriously! But severe or sudden swelling can be a sign of a serious problem, so let your doctor know ASAP.
            Changes in vaginal discharge. At 36 weeks pregnant, discharge may increase as your body readies itself for birth. But look out for watery discharge (which could be amniotic fluid—call your doctor!), blood (a sign of preterm labor), or mucus-like or blood-tinged discharge, which could be the mucus plug. Losing the mucus plug is a sign labor is very near. Just how near though, we can’t say!
            Braxton Hicks contractions. You’re probably still experiencing tightening in your abdomen, and it might be getting more intense. In fact, some pregnant women show up at the hospital thinking they’re in labor only to get turned away. Note that at 36 weeks pregnant, cramps that are at least as painful as menstrual cramps aren’t due to Braxton Hicks. If you’re experiencing something more severe, tell your OB right away.
            Because at 36 weeks pregnant signs of labor can tough to tell apart from regular pregnancy discomforts, you’ll want to tell your doctor if anything seems out of the ordinary. It’s worth the call. And yes, even a trip to the hospital to find out it’s false labor is totally okay. The worst that could happen is you get sent home to relax and wait.</symptoms>
        <belly>At 36 weeks, your pregnant belly probably won’t seem to change much from week to week. You’ve probably gained close to 25 to 35 pounds total—the recommended total amount of pregnancy weight gain for women of normal BMI. That’s probably making it challenging to move (or really… waddle) around. You won’t be putting on too much weight from here on out—probably only about a half-pound each week until baby’s born.
            If you’re 36 weeks pregnant with twins, you’ve probably gained 35 to 45 pounds total. To say your belly is crowded is an understatement. While many twin moms deliver around week 36, there’s a chance you and your pair might hold on for a few more weeks. Remember that the longer you go, the less likely it is that your babies will need NICU time after birth. So even if you’re feeling super uncomfortable, hang in there and remember this extra time in utero is so good for the twins!</belly>
        <checklist>1.Schedule your 37-week prenatal visit,2.Finalize your maternity-leave plan,3.Get answers to your labor and delivery questions,</checklist>
    </week36>

    <week37>
        <description>Time for some good clean… fun? Around week 37 of pregnancy, many moms-to-be find themselves organizing cupboards and scrubbing floors. That’s the phenomenon people lovingly refer to as “nesting.” It may be instinctual—your body senses baby will be here really soon. After all, you’re 37 weeks pregnant, which is considered “early term,” meaning baby is almost ready. Nesting can also be your brain’s way of trying to make sure you’re prepared for, well, as much as you can be prepared for. Having a baby-friendly pad definitely gives you an edge on this whole new parent thing. At least that’s one thing you can control!
            How Big Is Baby at 37 weeks?
            At 37 weeks pregnant, baby is the size of a head of romaine lettuce. Baby measures about 19.1 inches. Average baby weight at 37 weeks is 6.3 pounds, and baby is gaining about half an ounce each day.
            37 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            37 weeks pregnant is eight months and about one week. You’ve got just three weeks until your due date.</description>
        <symptoms>At 37 weeks pregnant, symptoms can be confused with signs of labor. Here’s what you might be feeling this week:
            Heartburn. Baby continues to put pressure on your digestive system as you near your due date.
            Spotting. A little bit of spotting is normal at week 37 of pregnancy—remember, your cervix is extra sensitive while you’re pregnant, so sex can irritate it and make it bleed. But call your doctor if it's more than just a few drops of blood. Vaginal bleeding could be a sign of a problem with the placenta (such as placental abruption) and it is important to seek treatment right away. Also, don’t confuse spotting or bleeding with the “bloody show,” a discharge tinged with blood that’s a totally harmless sign your cervix is changing to prep for delivery.
            Stretch marks. Sorry, but new stretchies might appear on your 37 weeks pregnant belly and each week from here on out. Keep that body oil on hand and lather up when you can. Also, keep drinking lots of water, even though you’re heading to the bathroom, oh, every two minutes.
            Abdominal pressure. If baby has dropped down into your pelvis in anticipation of labor, he or she is putting increased pressure on your abdomen, which might make you feel some new aches and pains down below—and a greater urge to pee too!
            Trouble sleeping. It’s normal to be up in the middle of the night in late pregnancy. Some strategies for getting more Zzzzs: Get plenty of light exercise during the day, drink lots of water—except right before bedtime—and limit your caffeine intake.
            Contractions. At 37 weeks, cramping or contractions are to be expected. After all, you’re going to have a baby soon—your body’s ramping up! You may find that your contractions go away if you sit or lie down. That means they’re Braxton Hicks—not real labor contractions. Make sure you stay hydrated, since dehydration could put you into early labor.
            Nausea. An upset stomach is pretty typical almost any time during pregnancy. But now that you’re so close to your due date, it could be a sign you’ll go into labor soon. (Whoa!) If your nausea is severe—if you’re vomiting especially—tell your OB so he or she can rule out illness or a pregnancy complication such as HELLP or preeclampsia.
            37 weeks pregnant with twins? 57 percent of twins are born before pregnancy week 37, so if your twosome is still hanging in there, you’re in the minority among moms of multiples. And while you’re probably feeling super uncomfortable and really antsy to get those babies out, you’re doing a really good thing for their health by sticking it out.</symptoms>
        <belly>37 weeks pregnant is the perfect time to brush up on the signs of labor. Each day, your likelihood of going into labor goes up, and who wants to be stuck in a car giving birth because they waited too long to get to the hospital? (We don’t mean to scare you—the chances you’ll give birth in a car are low. We just want you to be prepared.)
            The various signs of labor tend to fall into two categories—those that mean it’s coming soon and those that mean it’s happening now.
            You’ll go into labor soon if you notice these signs of labor at 37 weeks (though we can’t say how soon—every pregnancy is different. Sorry!):
            Mucus plug and/or bloody show. You may see a bit of thick mucus come out onto your underwear, either in one big glob or little by little. This is the mucus plug, which has been protecting your cervix all along. As your cervix dilates, the mucus plug is released to make way for baby. The mucus plug may or may not have a tinge of blood in it—if it does, that’s the “bloody show.”
            Nausea. Some women swear they start to feel sick to their stomach just before labor begins. So, at 37 weeks pregnant, nausea might mean baby’s coming soon.
            Diarrhea. When you’re 37 weeks pregnant, diarrhea could just be diarrhea or it could mean impending labor. That’s because as your hormones change to prep for delivery, they can also stimulate your bowels.
            Below are the signs labor is here—these mean a call to your OB right away:
            Water breaking. If you feel water leaking out—either in a gush or a trickle—that’s probably amniotic fluid. Most women go into labor within 12 hours of their water breaking.
            Regular contractions. Has your 37 weeks pregnant belly been tightening on the reg? If the contractions keep repeating and they seem to be coming more and more frequently, you’re in labor. As your uterus contracts, it’s dilating your cervix so baby can pass through at delivery. If this is your first pregnancy, you may have regular contractions for several hours before you go into what’s known as “active labor”—that’s when contractions get really painful and will require all your attention. (And when you should be at the hospital!)
            Back pain. Ah, the dreaded “back labor!” Sometimes baby’s positioned in a way that puts extra pressure on mom’s spine. If you get constant back pain that’s more severe than any you’ve had so far in pregnancy, or the pain radiates from your abdomen to your back (or vice versa), it could mean you’re in labor.
            Your doctor will tell you at what point to get your 37 weeks pregnant belly to the hospital. If your water has broken, your doctor could advise that you be admitted right away, because you may need to be monitored for infection. If you’re having contractions, they’ll probably need to be happen consistently five minutes or less apart before many hospitals will admit you, so the farther away you are, the sooner you’ll need to leave your home.
            At 37 weeks, many moms-to-be are dying to know how to induce labor. But don’t get ahead of yourself! A 37-week fetus is considered “early term.” That means doctors don’t recommend inducing or doing a c-section just yet. That’s because at 37 weeks pregnant, some babies need a couple more weeks to complete development. If you go into labor naturally, that’s totally cool, but there’s no need to rush things. Once you hit 39 weeks, which is considered “full term,” you can feel free to take a long walk, have sex, or have acupuncture done in hopes of naturally inducing labor. Those things are considered safe and may work (though none of them are proven!). But seriously, hang tight for a couple weeks. It can make a big difference in the health of your baby at birth. Consider it the first of many selfless acts of love that you will do for baby!</belly>
        <checklist>1.Schedule your 38-week prenatal visit,2.Learn the signs of postpartum depression,3.Brush up on baby grooming basics,</checklist>
    </week37>

    <week38>
        <description>Yow! If you feel a lightning bolt-like sensation running up and down your legs (and in your vagina!), don’t freak out. At 38 weeks pregnant, baby’s probably sitting pretty low in your pelvis, which means he or she is bumping into all kinds of nerves down there—including some super-sensitive ones you might not know you had. While you’re dealing with that new discomfort, be on the lookout for signs of labor at week 38 of pregnancy, including contractions that come on stronger, at more regular intervals, and of course, the “bloody show.” The big event could happen any day now—or it might not be for a few weeks. Until then, try to chill.
            How Big Is Baby at 38 Weeks Pregnant?
            At 38 weeks pregnant, baby is as big as a winter melon. Baby is about 19.6 inches long and his or her head is about the same circumference as the abdomen. Average baby weight at 38 weeks is 6.8 pounds. Sounds a lot like a birth weight, huh?
            38 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            38 weeks pregnant is eight months and about two weeks. You’re about to head down the home stretch of pregnancy.</description>
        <symptoms>Common 38 weeks pregnant symptoms have everything to do with being really, really pregnant. You’re big; your baby’s almost ready to arrive, and your body’s getting ready for D-day (that’s delivery day). Here’s how your body is affected:
            Braxton Hicks contractions. At 38 weeks pregnant, contractions are to be expected. You may have been having these for weeks now, or you may be just starting to notice what seems like 38 weeks pregnant cramps or tightening of your belly. If your contractions aren’t painful, and go away when you switch positions, they’re still Braxton Hicks (a.k.a. “practice” contractions).
            Trouble sleeping. Maybe you’re feeling anxious, or maybe it’s just all the aches and pains. But for someone who’s so tired, man it’s hard to get a good night’s rest!
            Increased vaginal discharge. You may begin to notice globs of a thick, mucus-like substance this week. This yucky stuff is called the mucus plug, and its presence is totally normal. It gets released as your cervix dilates in preparation for labor. Take heart; every bit of the mucus plug brings you that much closer to going into labor!
            Itchy belly. Your 38 weeks pregnant belly is stretched practically as far as it can go, so it makes sense that it’s more sensitive. Hydration can help: at this point in pregnancy, you may want to switch to a heavy-duty moisturizer like pure shea butter, and remember to drink lots of water. What’s not normal is a rash, so let your OB know if you get one.
            Swollen feet and ankles. You’re 38 weeks pregnant, so basically you have the excuse to sit back and put up your feet as much as humanly possible. Take regular walks though, to keep your blood flowing and reduce the swelling.
            Anxiety. It’s normal to be so over pregnancy by the time you reach 38 weeks pregnant. This feeling of being ready to Get. The. Baby. Out. might be even stronger if you’ve gained a significant amount of pregnancy weight, had a complicated pregnancy, or are 38 weeks pregnant with twins. Try to keep your mind occupied with fun things. Go see a movie, have a special dinner with your partner, or get together with some friends for lunch. These are your last days or weeks before a newborn takes up all your attention, so enjoy them as much as you can.</symptoms>
        <belly>At 38 weeks pregnant, signs of labor may begin. Some early signs you’ll go into labor soon include:
            Mucus plug and/or bloody show. You might have a discharge that’s thick like mucus (the mucus plug) and could have a slightly bloody tinge (the bloody show). This is a sign your cervix is starting to dilate in preparation for birth.
            Diarrhea. At 38 weeks pregnant, diarrhea might not be because of that spicy food you ate, it could be a sign that labor hormones are present in your body. It may be go time very soon.
            Nausea. Same goes for 38 weeks pregnant nausea. This isn’t a measurable sign of labor, but some women swear they felt queasy just before labor started.
            Contractions. At 38 weeks pregnant, contractions may be a normal part of your day—or maybe you haven’t noticed any yet. But know that if your 38 weeks pregnant belly starts tightening at regular intervals and doesn’t stop, then you’re likely in the early stages of labor. Painful contractions or ones that are closer than five minutes apart mean you should get to the hospital stat!
            Back pain. You may have had a sore back for weeks now, but at 38 weeks pregnant, back pain that’s intense or sudden could actually be back labor, so let your doctor know if you’re experiencing this 38 weeks pregnant symptom.
            Water breaking. If you feel a trickle of water, it means the amniotic sac has ruptured and the fluid is leaking out. Labor usually starts pretty soon after a woman’s water breaks, so let your OB know if you get this 38 weeks pregnant symptom.
            At 38 weeks pregnant, inducing labor may be medically necessary if you have a complication such as preeclampsia or gestational diabetes, a uterine infection, or a placental problem. Otherwise, if you’re 38 weeks pregnant with twins, or if you’re experiencing bleeding at 38 weeks pregnant, your doctor might say “It’s time!” This can send any mom-to-be who thought she had two more weeks into a panic, but know that everything will be okay. We can never really be 100 percent ready (well, maybe you’re one of those women who makes it to week 42), and you and baby are in good hands while under the care of your OB and the pediatrician.
            Remember, at 38 weeks pregnant inducing labor naturally isn’t recommended—baby usually needs a little more time on the inside—and some methods aren’t considered safe. So if you want to try to stimulate labor yourself, check with your doctor first, and wait at least another week for your baby to be “full term.”</belly>
        <checklist>1.Schedule your 39-week prenatal visit,2.Prep for breastfeeding,3.Cook and freeze some meals,</checklist>
    </week38>

    <week39>
        <description>Yay! Baby has finally reached full term! You’re probably feeling like you want to get this baby… The. Heck. Out. We’re not sure, but the impatience and discomfort moms-to-be feel around 39 weeks pregnant (and beyond!) might be nature’s way of getting you mentally prepared for delivery. Remember how freaked out you used to be about childbirth? Now, at week 39 of pregnancy, you don’t care what it takes, you just don’t want to be pregnant anymore!
            How Big Is Baby at 39 Weeks?
            At 39 weeks pregnant, baby is as big as a pumpkin. Your 39-week fetus measures about 20 inches long and weighs about 7.3 pounds. And baby just keeps growing, despite being so crowded inside your 39 weeks pregnant belly.
            39 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            39 weeks pregnant is eight months and three weeks pregnant. Next week, you’ll have completed nine months of pregnancy, and will reach your due date (that is, if you don’t go into labor this week). This is exciting!</description>
        <symptoms>Typical 39 weeks pregnant symptoms—the ones that aren’t signs labor is happening now—are similar to what you’ve been experiencing the past few weeks. Most are signs that labor will happen soon though. This includes:
            Braxton Hicks contractions. At 39 weeks pregnant, cramping or tightening of your uterus may seem pretty constant, no matter what you do. Usually these false labor pains start in the front of your body and ease up when you switch positions. You'll know it's real labor when they start at the top of your uterus and become more frequent and regular.
            Pelvic pressure. While getting into position for birth, baby may be sitting so low that that your lower torso feels heavy and uncomfortable.
            Lightning crotch. Because baby’s so low, his or her movements can hit some sensitive nerves, giving you sharp sensations in your pelvis—yep, like a lightning bolt! Yowch!
            Urge to nest. Some moms-to-be say they get a surge of energy and strong desire to clean their home right before baby’s debut. Don’t go too crazy though. You don’t want to wear yourself out before the birth.
            Mucus plug and/or bloody show. At 39 weeks pregnant, discharge that’s as thick as mucus and sometimes has a tinge of blood in it is your mucus plug. (The blood is, you guessed it, the bloody show.) And while many people consider this to be a sign you’ll go into labor soon, there’s no exact science to it, so it’s hard to say when.
            If you’re the rare mom-to-be who’s 39 weeks pregnant with twins, kudos to you! You’ve kept those babies baking despite the odds of an early delivery—and despite your all-around discomfort. You’re probably feeling many 39 weeks pregnant symptoms, including the urge to get your twosome out of your 39 weeks pregnant belly and into the world. Don’t worry—the end is so near!</symptoms>
        <belly>Other symptoms are your body’s way of telling you baby’s making his or her arrival ASAP. At 39 weeks pregnant, signs of labor are the biggest things on your mind. It’s important to know what they are, but don’t worry too much about going into labor without realizing it. In most cases, labor symptoms will be so strong and so different from what you’ve been experiencing that you won’t be able to ignore them.
            Call your OB if you experience either of these:
            Water breaking. It might not be like it is in the movies—you might have a slow trickle instead of a huge gush of water. But if at 39 weeks pregnant the discharge is watery instead of its usual consistency, that probably means your amniotic sac has ruptured and you will likely go into labor within hours.
            Regular contractions. If your belly’s tightening—and has been repeatedly for some time—start timing the contractions. If they keep coming and the time between them keeps getting shorter, you’re in the beginning stage of labor. Just how long this stage lasts will vary from mom to mom (yes, you’ll be a mom very soon!), so keep your OB updated, and follow his or her directions for getting to the hospital by the time you progress into active labor.
            When you’re 39 weeks pregnant, no signs of labor may have appeared yet, and that’s fine too! The average first-time mom-to-be goes into labor naturally at 41 weeks, and a second-time mom tends to go at 40 weeks. And while some women start to show signs of labor—a dilated and/or effaced cervix, regular contractions, etc.—weeks or days before they give birth, others go from zero to 10 centimeters dilated within hours.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Schedule your 40-week prenatal visit,2.Make a "baby's here!" contact list,3.Know what happens during delivery,4.Read other moms' birth stories</checklist>
    </week39>

    <week40>
        <description>Happy due date! Since 40 weeks pregnant is baby’s official deadline, you’ve already made up the bassinet, installed baby’s car seat, packed your hospital bag, and set it by the door. Now, take care of some easy last-minute things, like making sure your cell phone is fully charged before you go to bed and filling the car with gas. At week 40 of pregnancy, some moms-to-be put a waterproof mattress cover on their bed, in case their water breaks in the middle of the night. It’s not a must, but it’s not a bad idea either, especially because once baby comes, there might be other messes to catch (breast milk, spit up, pee…). Week 40 of pregnancy can be mentally rough, since you’ll be constantly wondering when baby will decide to make his or her entrance and question every twinge you have. Try not to stress, and rest assured that baby will arrive when he or she's ready—and your body will give you the right signals that it’s time.
            How Big Is Baby at 40 Weeks Pregnant?
            At 40 weeks pregnant, baby is the size of a watermelon. The average full-term 40- week baby measures about 20.2 inches from crown to heel and weighs 7.6 pounds.
            40 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            40 weeks pregnant is nine months. Say it again because it feels good: Nine. Months. Pregnant. You made it!</description>
        <symptoms>During these last weeks of pregnancy, the same symptoms you’ve been having will likely continue. Your main job is to hang in there as you keep experiencing these:
            Leg cramps. Stick with the calf and hamstring stretches to keep leg cramps from messing with your sleep. Pelvic pressure. Baby may drop even lower in your pelvis, making your pelvic discomfort worse.
            Trouble sleeping. If you can’t sleep, it’s okay to get up and do something else, but keep to a calming activity such as reading or writing in a journal. Don’t start cleaning out your freezer or doing a Zumba video. Rest.
            Fatigue. The fact that you can’t sleep isn’t really helping here. But since you may not have any plans, you may be able to sneak in an extra nap here or there—or at least take some quiet time to relax.
            Contractions. Those Braxton Hicks contractions may eventually turn into the real deal, so if it seems like you’re having a lot of them, start timing them to see how far apart they are. If they get closer together, you’re in an early stage of labor.
            Anxiety! Baby will get here when he or she gets here. Do your best not to stress.</symptoms>
        <belly>You might be 40 weeks pregnant with no signs of labor. But at 40 weeks pregnant, signs of labor will be here very soon. Call your doctor right away if you have contractions that are more than a little uncomfortable or keep coming at regular intervals. The other 40 weeks pregnant sign of labor to look out for? A leak or flow of amniotic fluid—this means your water has ruptured or broken. You’ll likely know because it will be truly watery, not like typical discharge, and it doesn’t stop. At first you might think it’s pee, but then you will realize—nope! You’re in labor! Call your OB.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Schedule your 41-week prenatal visit,2.Talk to your doctor about induction options,3.If your doctor orders it, have a non-stress test,</checklist>
    </week40>

    <week41>
        <description>Bet you never envisioned being 41 weeks pregnant. But here you are! Because of your baby's extra time in the womb, he or she'll likely be heavier and more alert at birth than a baby born earlier would be. At week 41 of pregnancy, the anticipation might feel like it’s killing you, but rest assured that plenty of moms-to-be go past their due date and everything turns out just fine. You might actually be thankful to have had this extra time before dirty diapers and newborn feedings rule your world.
            How Big Is Baby at 41 Weeks?
            At 41 weeks, baby is as big as a watermelon. The average 41-week fetus measures 20.4 inches long and weighs 7.9 pounds.
            41 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            41 weeks pregnant is nine months and one week pregnant. Consider yourself an overachiever!</description>
        <symptoms>Common 41 weeks pregnant symptoms are a continuation of your other third trimester symptoms. Most notably:
            Pelvic discomfort. Baby may be descending lower and lower, putting pressure on your bladder and cervix and giving you more aches and pains down below.
            Hemorrhoids. That pelvic pressure causes swollen varicose veins in your rectum, causing hemorrhoids. They aren’t pretty, and they may get worse when you push baby out. But eventually the swelling will die down.
            Difficulty sleeping. It's the hormones—and your nerves!—that are keeping you from getting a good night’s sleep. You’re not going to be sleeping much after baby arrives, so this is good practice. But it’s also a good idea to rest up as much as possible for the birth.
            Frequent urination. Baby's pretty much sitting right on your bladder at this point. Cue another trip to the bathroom!
            Contractions. Abdominal tightening is happening more and more noticeably and frequently as baby ramps up for delivery.</symptoms>
        <belly>By the time you hit 41 weeks pregnant, signs of labor might as well be written inside your eyelids. You probably know this stuff by heart! But just in case, here goes. Call the doctor if you have:
            A constant leak which may indicate your water has broken.
            Frequent or painful contractions that don’t stop.
            You will also want to call the doctor if you have any out-of-the ordinary 41 weeks pregnant symptoms, such as bleeding or abdominal pain.
            If you’re 41 weeks with no signs of labor, try to be patient! Just because you’re 41 weeks and not dilated doesn’t mean you can’t go into labor tomorrow. It’s really unpredictable like that!</belly>
        <checklist>1.Make your induction appointment, if you’ve chosen to have it done,2.Rest up for delivery,3.Binge watch some TV!,4.Take a long walk</checklist>
    </week41>

    <week42>
        <description>Welcome to a “post-term” pregnancy. If you’re reading this, you’re one of the rare moms-to-be who makes it to 42 weeks pregnant. Don’t let all those people asking you where your baby is and why you haven’t been induced make you feel like something’s wrong. Every mom-to-be and baby is different and your due date is just an estimate—sometimes due dates are miscalculated too! So, there’s absolutely nothing wrong with making it to week 42 of pregnancy. And while you might feel like you’re going a little crazy with anxiety, remember: 98 percent of babies emerge by the end of week 42. So you’ll get to meet baby really soon—we promise!
            How Big Is Baby at 42 Weeks?
            At 42 weeks pregnant, baby is the size of a watermelon—a bigger watermelon than last week. The average 42-week fetus measures 20.3 inches and weighs 8.1 pounds. Yup, baby’s still growing! But don’t worry, he or she is unlikely to be too big to deliver vaginally.
            42 Weeks Pregnant Is How Many Months?
            42 weeks pregnant is nine months and two weeks. Yes, it happens!</description>
        <symptoms>Your 42 weeks pregnant symptoms are probably the same ones you’ve been feeling the past few weeks—leg cramps, trouble sleeping, backaches, pelvic pressure, hemorrhoids, frequent urination, contractions—just maybe more intense.
            You might be stressed at 42 weeks pregnant. No one said pregnancy after 40 weeks was easy! Try to be patient as you let baby decide when to make his or her debut.
            Know that at 42 weeks pregnant, risks are higher for complications such as placental problems, low amniotic fluid, and a pinched umbilical cord. And baby’s at a slightly higher risk of having to go to the NICU. Keep doing kick counts and letting your OB know if you notice any changes in kick frequency. Also tell your doctor right away if you have any troubling 42 weeks pregnant symptoms, such as strange discharge, bleeding, or abdominal pain.</symptoms>
        <belly>At 42 weeks pregnant signs of labor—the ones you’ve been waiting for!—may begin. Look out for:
            Mucus plug and/or bloody show. The thick mucus discharge—sometimes tinged with blood—is a sign the cervix is getting itself ready for delivery. It’s often a sign labor will start soon. Though just how soon, we can’t predict!
            Water breaking. If you’re leaking amniotic fluid or if your water breaks in one huge gush, call your doctor. Labor will probably begin within hours.
            Regular contractions. Hallelujah! This sign you’re in labor is the one you’ve probably been anticipating most. These guys are more intense than any Braxton Hicks contractions you may have been having, and most importantly, they don’t go away. True labor contractions happen over and over, at shorter intervals, and at higher intensity (ouch!), and don’t let up until baby is born. (Yay!)
            Wondering how to induce labor at 42 weeks pregnant? You probably have been trying natural methods such as walking, sex, and acupuncture. But don’t resort to drinking castor oil (you’ll probably just make yourself sick), taking herbal supplements (they could be dangerous to you and baby), or stimulating your nipples (the resulting contractions could be too strong and dangerous for baby).
            Because at 42 weeks pregnant risks increase, your doctor may recommend a medical labor induction if tests show it isn’t safe for baby to stay in utero much longer. Ways your doctor can induce labor are:
            Stripping the membranes. At 42 weeks pregnant, this technique might be the thing that sets your body over the edge. Your doctor uses a finger to swipe around the amniotic sac. The hormones released often cause contractions within 48 hours.
            Breaking your water. Using an instrument that looks like plastic hook, your doctor breaks the amniotic sac. This can cause contractions in just hours.
            Ripening your cervix. A medication called prostaglandin is inserted vaginally overnight in order to dilate the cervix.
            Stimulating contractions. You’ll be hooked up to an IV with a synthetic version of the hormone oxytocin. This medication can get contractions started.</belly>
        <checklist>1.Take more long walks,2.Discuss 42 weeks pregnant risks with your OB,3.Have sex (if you can swing it!),4.Try to relax!,</checklist>
    </week42>

</week>
